[
  {
    "question": "A network technician has configured a wireless router so that stations must be authenticated before allowing network access. What did he configure?",
    "options": [
      "WPA PSK",
      "WPA2 PSK",
      "WEP",
      "802.1x"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 802.1x is correct. 802.1x requires authentication to a central authentication server before allowing network access. The client network connection, whether wireless or through a physical switch port, is not fully functional until successful authentication is achieved. Incorrect answers: WEP is incorrect. Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP) is a deprecated wireless network security protocol. WPA PSK and WPA2 PSK are incorrect. WPA and WPA2 PSK uses a passphrase on both sides of a connection to secure wireless network transmissions, but they do not enforce network level authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are steps in collecting digital evidence except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Acquire the evidence.",
      "Judge the evidence.",
      "Seize the evidence.",
      "Verify the evidence."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Judge the evidence is correct. Judging the evidence is not the job of the computer forensics examiner, and this is not a step involved in collecting the digital evidence. The major steps are to seize evidence from the scene, acquire it using forensically proven processes, verify that the acquired evidence is identical to the original evidence through hashing tools, analyze the evidence, and report the findings. Incorrect answer: Seize the evidence is incorrect. The first of the major steps is to seize evidence from the scene. Acquire the evidence is incorrect. The second of the major steps is to acquire the evidence using forensically proven processes. Verify the evidence is incorrect. The third of the major steps is to verify that the acquired evidence is identical to the original evidence through hashing tools."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are examples of spyware? (Choose three.)",
    "options": [
      "Flooding a host with network traffic",
      "Gathering entered user keystrokes",
      "Manipulating search engine results",
      "Broadcasting ARP cache updates to network hosts",
      "Changing the web browser home page"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      2,
      4
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answers: Gathering entered user keystrokes, Manipulating search engine results, and Changing the web browser home page are correct. Spyware can capture all entered keystrokes and send them to interested parties, search results can be manipulated to trick users into clicking links to certain advertisements for example, and the web browser home page be changed, thus forcing the user to view a web page when she starts her web browser. In some cases the home page cannot be easily changed. Incorrect Answers: Flooding a host with network traffic is incorrect. Intentional network traffic flooding is considered a DoS (denial of service) attack that denies legitimate access to a service, but this would not be spyware. Traffic floods can be mitigated with flood guards, which come in the form of separate appliances or could be built into a network switch. Broadcasting ARP cache updates to network hosts is incorrect. ARP cache updates may indicate an ARP poisoning attack and may be discovered using the arp command to view the ARP cache, but this is not related to spyware."
  },
  {
    "question": "You would like to ensure that an authentication server is always available. Two authentication servers are clustered together with the authentication data stored on shared disk storage. What must be done to eliminate any single points of failure? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Configure the shared disk storage with RAID 1.",
      "Add a third server to the cluster.",
      "Enable a second NIC in each cluster node.",
      "Enable all CPU cores."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Enable a second NIC in each cluster node and Configure the shared disk storage with RAID 1 are correct. A second NIC (network interface card) ensures that network communication continues if one NIC fails. With RAID level 1, also called disk mirroring, data written to one disk is also written to a second disk for safety. Incorrect answers: Add a third server to the cluster is incorrect. Having two servers in a cluster eliminates the server as being a single point of failure; a third server is not required. Configure the shared disk storage with RAID 1 is incorrect. Enabling all CPU cores may improve performance or workload capacity, but it does not remove any single points of failure."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of policy outlines how customer data is acquired, used, and stored?",
    "options": [
      "Acceptable use",
      "Secret",
      "Privacy",
      "Encryption"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Privacy is correct. Privacy policies outline how data is gathered, managed, and stored. Regional and industry laws may also influence privacy policies. Incorrect answers: Acceptable use is incorrect. Acceptable use policies state how company assets and computer systems are to be properly used to conduct business. Secret and Encryption are incorrect. Secrecy and encryption policies are not industry-standard terms, although they may be defined within a policy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of restriction requires an account to become unusable after a certain period of time or a certain date?",
    "options": [
      "Account disablement",
      "Account expiration",
      "Account lockout",
      "Time-of-day restriction"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Account expiration is correct. Account expiration is a restriction that forces an account to become unusable after a certain duration (after 90 days, for example) or after a certain date, and it's typically used with temporary employees. Incorrect answers: Time-of-day restriction is incorrect. A time-of-day restriction prevents users from logging in during certain hours, such as during off-work hours or weekends. Account lockout is incorrect. Account lockout specifies a threshold for invalid attempts at logging in and will render the account unusable after that threshold has been reached. Account disablement is incorrect. Disabling an account is typically at the discretion of management or an administrator and could happen any time the user is seen as a security risk or does not require the account for an indefinite period."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following algorithms is the stronger hashing algorithm?",
    "options": [
      "3DES",
      "AES-256",
      "MD5",
      "SHA-1"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SHA-1 is correct. SHA-1 (Secure Hash Algorithm) generates a 160-bit hash. Incorrect answers: 3DES is incorrect. 3DES is a symmetric encryption algorithm, not a hashing algorithm. MD5 is incorrect. MD5 is a hashing algorithm that generates a 128-bit hash, which is weaker than SHA-1. AES-256 is incorrect. AES-256 is a symmetric encryption algorithms, not a hashing algorithm."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following commonly result from spyware infections? (Choose three.)",
    "options": [
      "Slower computer",
      "Identity theft",
      "Money stolen through online banking",
      "Reformatted hard disk"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      1,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answers: Identity theft, Money stolen through online banking, and Slower computer are correct. Spyware can track your computing habits, including web sites you visit, things you type in, programs you use, and so on. This can lead to identity theft and financial theft, and it can slow down your computer, since spyware is present and running all the time. Incorrect Answer: Reformatted hard disk is incorrect. Spyware would not reformat your hard disk, although many viruses could."
  },
  {
    "question": "A Linux administrator enables hardware disk encryption for data drives used by a Linux server. The operating system disk is physically located in the Linux server but the data drives exist on a SAN (storage area network). Which of the following statements is true?",
    "options": [
      "Disk encryption is not possible for SAN disks.",
      "Linux cannot use SAN disks.",
      "The confidentiality of the data is being protected.",
      "The integrity of the data is being protected."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: The confidentiality of the data is being protected is correct. Encryption protects data confidentially. Only authorized parties possessing the correct decryption keys can access encrypted data. Incorrect answers: The integrity of the data is being protected is incorrect. File system data integrity would be provided by digital signing or file hashes, but not by encryption. Disk encryption is not possible for SAN disks is incorrect. Hardware disk encryption on a server is often done with TPM, which is a firmware chip storing cryptographic keys. Linux cannot use SAN disks is incorrect. SAN disks appear to the OS as local disks; Linux does support the use of SAN disks."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the security administrator for a small company and would like to limit clients that can connect to the wireless network by hardware address. What would you do?",
    "options": [
      "Implement MAC filtering.",
      "Implement WEP.",
      "Enable SSID cloaking.",
      "Implement NAC."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Implement MAC filtering is correct. MAC address filtering, although not an effective security measure by itself, can be used to limit which clients, by hardware address, can connect to the wireless network. Incorrect answers: Implement WEP is incorrect. WEP is a wireless security protocol. Implement NAC is incorrect. NAC prevents clients from connecting that do not meet specified security requirements, such as patch level or antivirus signature. Enable SSID cloaking is incorrect. SSID cloaking merely prevents potential wireless clients from seeing the wireless network name by stopping it from being broadcast."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two activities commonly result from hacker-controlled botnets consisting of many infected computers?",
    "options": [
      "DDoS",
      "Spyware",
      "Spam",
      "Ransomware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answers: DDoS and Spam are correct. Botnets are collections of computers under hacker control. Spam messages or distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks are easily launched from botnets because of the number of controlled computers. DDoS mitigators use techniques such as up-to-date IP reputation databases to detect attacks. Incorrect Answers: Spyware is incorrect. Spyware monitors user activity without user consent. Ransomware is incorrect. Ransomware encrypts data files without user consent and requires a ransom payment to potentially receive a decryption key."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager asks you to identify the amount of time and personnel required to address a worm virus infection on the corporate WAN. You estimate it would take six technicians two days to remove the infection, at a total cost of $2800. Which type of analysis would this dollar figure best relate to?",
    "options": [
      "ARO analysis",
      "Business impact analysis",
      "Quantitative risk analysis",
      "ALE analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Business impact analysis is correct. A business impact analysis studies the impact (financial in this case) that an incident presents to a business. Incorrect answers: Quantitative risk analysis is incorrect. Quantitative risk analysis uses ALE (annual loss expectancy) values to prioritize risks. The ALE is calculated by multiplying the ARO by the SLE value. The $2,800 is an SLE value, but the scenario does not offer an ARO value; thus, B is incorrect. ALE analysis and ARO analysis are incorrect because there is no such thing as an ALE or ARO analysis; they are used to perform a risk analysis."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of security testing does not provide any information at all to testers?",
    "options": [
      "Laterally known environment",
      "Known environment",
      "Partially known environment",
      "Unknown environment"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Unknown environment is correct. Unknown environment security testing does not provide any information on software coding, network layout or addressing, phone numbers, usernames, and so on. Testers must piece together relevant data to construct a picture of what they are testing. Incorrect answers: Known environment is incorrect. Known environment testers are given detailed information about the item they are testing. Partially known environment is incorrect. Partially known environment testing provides testers with a minimum of data regarding the test target. Laterally known environment is incorrect. Laterally known environment security testing is not a standard industry term."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company uses FTP servers to enable remote user access to sensitive corporate contracts. Which options will secure the FTP server communication? (Choose three.)",
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "IPSec",
      "TLS",
      "TPM"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      1,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: VPN, TLS, and IPSec are correct. FTP (File Transfer Protocol) servers transmit data (including credentials) in clear text. Remote user access to the FTP servers would be secured through a VPN (virtual private network). Some FTP servers support TLS to encrypt FTP packets. IPSec can be used to secure any type of IP traffic, including FTP. IPsec tunnel mode is used to create a secured tunnel between two endpoints. IPsec transport mode is normally used between communicating stations where all data above the IP header is encrypted and replaced with an encapsulation security payload (ESP) header. The authentication header (AH) doesn't encrypt data but is used to verify the integrity of the transmission. Incorrect answer: TPM is incorrect. TPM has nothing to do with securing data transmissions; it refers to hard disk encryption."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are performing a penetration test for your company and would like to collect publicly available information about your company using an OSINT tool. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "netcat",
      "nslookup",
      "nmap",
      "theHarvester"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: theHarvester is correct. theHarvester is an OSINT tool that is used to collect information from the Internet about a company related to e-mail addresses, domain names, host names, employee names, and open ports on the hosts. Incorrect answers: nslookup is incorrect. nslookup is a tool used to query DNS. nmap is incorrect. nmap is a port scanner used to identify services running on a system. netcat is incorrect. netcat is a tool used to open a port on a system and establish a connection to that port."
  },
  {
    "question": "With asymmetric encryption, which of the following is used to encrypt a message sent from Bob to Sue?",
    "options": [
      "Bob's private key",
      "Sue's public key",
      "Sue's private key",
      "Bob's public key"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Sue's public key is correct. Sue's public key is used to encrypt a message from Bob to Sue, as only Sue's private key can decrypt it. Incorrect answers: Sue's private key is incorrect. Sue's private key can only decrypt the message, and Bob does not possess it. Bob's public key is incorrect. Bob's public key can be used to encrypt a message that is being sent to Bob. Bob's private key is incorrect. Bob's private key is used to digital sign a message being sent by Bob, not encrypt a message being sent to Sue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following devices is intentionally left nonsecure, with the hopes of luring a hacker away from the network and observing them?",
    "options": [
      "IPS",
      "IDS",
      "Honeypot",
      "Bastion host"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Honeypot is correct. A honeypot is a host that has been left with some vulnerabilities open to lure a hacker away from attacking the network and to observe their attack methods. Incorrect answers: Bastion host is incorrect. A bastion host is a secure host outside the network. IDS is incorrect. An intrusion detection system (IDS) is used to detect network attacks. IPS is incorrect. An intrusion prevention system (IPS) is used to detect attacks and attempt to prevent them by rerouting traffic, blocking ports, and so on."
  },
  {
    "question": "Marcel, a security specialist, configures a network appliance to detect and block suspicious network activity. What has Marcel configured?",
    "options": [
      "Anomaly-based NIPS",
      "Anomaly-based NIDS",
      "Signature-based NIDS",
      "Host-based NIDS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Anomaly-based NIPS is correct. Suspicious network activity does not resemble a normal baseline of activity. This network deviation is referred to as an anomaly. NIPSs (network intrusion prevention systems) analyze suspicious activity and can be configured to prevent the activity from continuing. Incorrect answers: Signature-based NIDS is incorrect. A signature-based analysis compares network activity against known existing network attacks. Host-based NIDS is incorrect. A host-based NIDS analyzes activity specific to that host, not the network beyond that host. Anomaly-based NIDS is incorrect. An anomaly-based NIDS (network intrusion detection system) analysis compares network activity against a known normal baseline, which is unique for each network. It is important to note that NIDSs detect and report suspicious activity but do nothing to prevent it from continuing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which authentication method allows a user to authenticate to the network once and access multiple systems without needing to provide additional credentials?",
    "options": [
      "Kerberos",
      "PKI",
      "Multifactor",
      "Single sign-on"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Single sign-on is correct. Single sign-on (SSO) is a method that allows a user to authenticate to the network once and access multiple systems without needing to provide additional credentials. It could use several different technologies to achieve this, including username/password and multifactor authentication. Incorrect answers: PKI is incorrect. Public key infrastructure (PKI) manages the life cycles of digital certificates. Multifactor is incorrect. Multifactor authentication is an authentication method that uses multiple factors and can be used in a single sign-on environment. Kerberos is incorrect. Kerberos is an authentication protocol and also could be implemented in a single sign-on environment, but does not require it."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the past, your company has experienced malware unleashed on your LAN through users clicking malicious web site links in e-mail messages. What can you do to prevent this occurrence?",
    "options": [
      "Enable e-mail digital signatures.",
      "Encrypt the contents of hard disks.",
      "Install a personal firewall on all computers.",
      "Provide malware training to users."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Provide malware training to users is correct. User education and awareness go a long way toward protecting your network. Demonstrating examples of phishing attacks will enable users to make informed decisions about suspicious e-mail messages. Incorrect answers: Encrypt the contents of hard disks is incorrect. While important in securing sensitive data, encryption itself does not prevent malware infections. Enable e-mail digital signatures is incorrect. Digital signatures provide assurance to a recipient that a message is authentic, but this does not prevent malware infections. Install a personal firewall on all computers is incorrect. Some personal firewall software can identify suspicious e-mail messages, but ultimately the user decides what links to click."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are responsible for the Wi-Fi network at your company. How can you prevent the discovery of your WLAN from war drivers?",
    "options": [
      "Enable WPA2.",
      "Disable SSID broadcasting.",
      "Enable WEP.",
      "Enable MAC address filtering."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Disable SSID broadcasting is correct. If you disable SSID broadcasting, the WLAN name is not broadcast in the vicinity. Signal strength can also be configured to control how far Wi-Fi access is made available. Despite this fact, there are freely available tools (such as the Linux tool kismet) that will display non-broadcasting WLANs within range. Incorrect answers: Enable WEP is incorrect. WEP is a deprecated and vulnerable wireless security standard and should not be used; it does not control wireless network visibility. Enable WPA2 is incorrect. WPA2, now superseded by WPA3, is a wireless network security standard; it does not control wireless network visibility. Enable MAC address filtering is incorrect. MAC address filtering can control which devices can connect to the wireless network, but it does not prevent the network from being discovered by war drivers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your boss asks you to calculate the ALE value related to database server downtime. Which two numeric values do you need?",
    "options": [
      "Return on investment",
      "Single loss expectancy",
      "Total cost of ownership",
      "Annual rate of occurrence"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Annual rate of occurrence and Single loss expectancy are correct. ALE (annual loss expectancy) is used for quantitative risk analysis to assign a cost to a probable risk. The ARO (annual rate of occurrence) is a derived figure multiplied by the SLE (single loss expectancy) dollar value, resulting in the ALE. The ALE is then used to budget funds for dealing with the risk. Incorrect answers: Return on investment is incorrect. The return on investment (ROI) determines the benefits of an asset over time compared to resources invested. Total cost of ownership is incorrect. The total cost of ownership (TCO) focuses only on costs related to assets and related expenses over time, not the benefits derived from the use of that assets."
  },
  {
    "question": "Tanya wants to impress her computer science friends by gaining access to a server housed in a nearby central office owned by the local telephone carrier. She begins by researching the local telephone carrier on the Internet. Later that evening, Tanya sifts through the garbage bins on the local telephone carrier's premises and discovers printed memos and server configuration documentation. Tanya succeeds in gaining access to a local telephone carrier's server. What led to her success?",
    "options": [
      "Tailgating",
      "Dumpster diving",
      "Shoulder surfing",
      "Impersonation"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Dumpster diving is correct. Dumpster diving entails digging through discarded items and trash in search of meaningful information such as passcodes, e-mail addresses, server names, network documentation, and so on. Incorrect Answer: Tailgating is incorrect. Tailgating involves an unauthorized person following an authorized person who has access into a facility or areas within a facility. Shoulder surfing is incorrect. Shoulder surfing occurs when a person in close proximity to a user watches what the user is doing and typing in. Impersonation is incorrect. Impersonation involves giving the impression that you are someone other than who you really are, or that your network identity or network transmission is something other than what it really is."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are installing a wireless router on the first floor of a commercial building. What should you do to minimize the possibility of Wi-Fi users connecting from the street? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Place the wireless router in the center of the building.",
      "Disable DHCP on the wireless router.",
      "Disable DNS on the wireless router.",
      "Set the SSID to “Floor 1.”"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Place the wireless router in the center of the building and Disable DHCP on the wireless router are correct. Placing the wireless router in the center of the building reduces the signal strength outside of the building. Disabling DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) means connecting clients must manually configure an appropriate IP address, subnet mask, default gateway, and DNS server. Incorrect answers: Set the SSID to “Floor 1.” is incorrect. SSID broadcasting should be disabled, not set to something that implies a physical location. Disable DNS on the wireless router is incorrect. Disabling DNS is not normally done to harden a wireless network. If it is disabled, wireless clients must simply point to a different DNS server."
  },
  {
    "question": "Evidence must meet all of the following requirements to be admissible in court except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Incriminating",
      "Relevant",
      "Sufficient",
      "Competent"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Incriminating is correct. Evidence does not have to necessarily incriminate. It can also be exculpatory (proving someone innocent). Incorrect answers: Sufficient is incorrect. For evidence to be considered sufficient, it must provide a fact by itself, without the need for supporting evidence to prove the point. Competent is incorrect. The evidence must also be competent, which means that the evidence must have been legally obtained. If the evidence has been illegally obtained, it is inadmissible in court. Relevant is incorrect. The evidence must have relevance, meaning that it must be related to and have meaning for the case."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of system would be used for monitoring and notification of real-time data at a manufacturing site?",
    "options": [
      "SCADA",
      "Virtualization",
      "Cloud computing",
      "SNMP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SCADA is correct. Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition (SCADA) consists of hardware and software components to acquire data, monitor equipment, and notify of any hazardous conditions that may exist. The data is gathered and manipulated in real time. SCADA is often used in industrial control system (ICS) environments. Incorrect answers: SNMP is incorrect. Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) is used to monitor specific values, or counters, for network devices. Cloud computing is incorrect. Cloud computing offers IT services over a network. These services can be rapidly provisioned and deprovisioned from a self-service web portal, and usage is metered. Virtualization is incorrect. Virtualization enables multiple operating system to run concurrently on a single set of computing hardware."
  },
  {
    "question": "After downloading and attempting to install a video driver you downloaded from a vendor web site, your virus scanner reports that the file is suspicious. You update your virus scanner and scan the file but no viruses are found. What term describes this situation?",
    "options": [
      "False compromise",
      "False negative",
      "False positive",
      "Infection"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: False positive is correct. Report of a problem when none exists is a false positive. Incorrect answers: Infection is incorrect. Infection does not apply since the file is not actually infected. False compromise is incorrect. False compromise is an invalid term in this context. False negative is incorrect. The lack of reporting a problem when one does exist defines a false negative."
  },
  {
    "question": "You would like to perform a vulnerability scan on the network. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "nmap",
      "hping",
      "chmod",
      "Nessus"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Nessus is correct. Nessus is a vulnerability scanner that can be used to scan systems on the network and discover vulnerabilities that exists with each system. Incorrect answers: hping is incorrect. hping is a ping program for changing the protocol and port number used when a ping occurs. nmap is incorrect. nmap is a port scanner used to discover services running on a system. chmod is incorrect. chmod is a Linux command used to modify permissions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of planning relates to the recovery of a specific system?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact analysis",
      "Communication plan",
      "Disaster recovery plan",
      "Risk assessment"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Disaster recovery plan is correct. A disaster recovery plan provides step-by-step procedures to return a failed system to a functional state in as little time as possible. Incorrect answers: Business impact analysis is incorrect. A business impact analysis identifies the impact that realized threats could have on an organization's business processes. Risk assessment is incorrect. A risk assessment identifies assets and threats to those assets. A risk register can then be populated, with each risk assigned a severity level; this facilitates the prioritization of risk-mitigation solutions. Communication plan is incorrect. A communication plan is related to incident response in that a set of procedures are followed to communicate each phase of the response to the appropriate parties, including escalating to other teams."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of scan sends a packet to each port with the PSH, URG, and FIN flags set?",
    "options": [
      "ACK",
      "SYN",
      "XMAS",
      "TCP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: XMAS is correct. XMAS scans set three of the six TCP flags: PSH, URG, and FIN. Incorrect answers: TCP is incorrect. A TCP scan is a full scan that executes a full three-way handshake with the target system. Although this is the most type of accurate scan, it is also the one most likely to be detected (that is, it's the noisiest). SYN is incorrect. A SYN scan is stealthy and sends only a SYN packet to each port. ACK is incorrect. An ACK scan sets only the ACK flag. Note that all of these scans are performed against a target host to elicit a response, which, based on how the target reacts to each type of scan, can give the attacker valuable information about the target."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of log would list failed logon attempts?",
    "options": [
      "Event log",
      "Application log",
      "Security log",
      "Access log"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Security log is correct. The Windows Security log shows auditing entries related to activity such as logon attempts or file access. Incorrect answers: Access log, Event log, and Application log are incorrect. They are not as likely to contain failed logon attempts as an audit log is."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack executes code by overwriting areas of memory that should not be overwritten?",
    "options": [
      "Integer overflow",
      "DLL injection",
      "Buffer overflow",
      "Pointer dereference"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Buffer overflow is correct. Most applications reserve memory and expect a certain type and amount of data to use those memory addresses. Writing beyond these “buffers” into unallocated memory space with specially crafted code could execute that code on a remote system with elevated privileges. Memory not returned to the operating system presents a memory leak issue, which can eventually exhaust memory resource and prevent system functionality. Incorrect Answers: Integer overflow is incorrect. Integer overflows result from mathematical calculations resulting in numbers larger than the integer variable used to hold that value. Pointer dereference is incorrect. Dereferenced pointers contain a null value instead of valid data, which can result in an application crash. DLL injection is incorrect. DLL injection attacks replace valid dynamic-link libraries (DLLs) with malicious variants. Function calls to the malicious DLLs can then compromise a system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of risk analysis weighs potential threats based on dollar figures?",
    "options": [
      "ARO",
      "Quantitative",
      "Qualitative",
      "ALE"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Quantitative is correct. Quantitative risk analysis identifies assets and risks and uses calculations such as ALE (annual loss expectancy) to prioritize and budget funds to manage these risks. Incorrect answers: ALE and ARO are incorrect. ALE is a dollar amount derived from multiplying the ARO (annual rate of occurrence) by the SLE (single loss expectancy) and is used in quantitative risk analysis. Qualitative is incorrect. Qualitative risk analysis does not rank risks strictly by dollar amount; for example, it may involve a relative ranking in terms of the effect on the business."
  },
  {
    "question": "While discussing incident response policies during a meeting, your boss requests a dollar figure and the amount of downtime the company would suffer if a worm infected the corporate LAN. What type of study should you conduct?",
    "options": [
      "Risk analysis",
      "Packet analysis",
      "Vulnerability analysis",
      "Business impact analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Business impact analysis is correct. Studying the effect of unfavorable events (such as a computer worm) upon business operations is referred to as a business impact analysis. Incorrect answers: Risk analysis is incorrect. A risk analysis identifies objects that must be protected from risks and then prioritizes those items. Packet analysis is incorrect. Packet analysis involves studying network traffic and is not tied to corporate downtime due to worms. Vulnerability analysis is incorrect. A vulnerability analysis identifies security risks but not their impact on business operations."
  },
  {
    "question": "A company requires that traveling users have secure access to the corporate LAN across the Internet. Which technology provides this solution?",
    "options": [
      "Proxy server",
      "VPN",
      "Packet filtering firewall",
      "NAT"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: VPN is correct. VPN technology establishes an encrypted tunnel between a traveling user's computer and a VPN concentrator on a corporate network over an untrusted network, such as the Internet. Any data transmitted through the encrypted tunnel is secure and is decrypted by the other endpoint device. VPN split tunneling enables user access to corporate resources while still allowing access to Internet resources through the user's Internet connection. Incorrect answer: NAT is incorrect. Network address translation (NAT) is commonly used to enable multiple internal computers to gain public network access using a single public IP address of the NAT public interface. Packet filtering firewall is incorrect. A packet filtering firewall allows or restricts packets based on packet address and protocol information. Proxy server is incorrect. Proxy servers are used to fetch Internet content requested by internal users. The proxy server can also be configured to cache content for a specified amount of time so that subsequent requests for that content are satisfied locally instead of from the Internet."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have an Internet-facing web server that only serves static web pages to users. Recently you have discovered that someone has been using your server as a mail relay. Which service and port should you remove to stop this type of attack?",
    "options": [
      "HTTP, port 80",
      "SMTP, port 25",
      "HTTP, port 443",
      "SMTP, port 110"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SMTP and port 25 is correct. Simple Mail Transport Protocol (SMTP) uses TCP port 25 and is used to send e-mail, and it should not be running on an Internet-facing server that only provides a web site. Incorrect answers: HTTP and port 80 is incorrect. HTTP (port 80) must be allowed to run on the server to provide web content to users. SMTP and port 110 is incorrect. SMTP uses port 25, not port 110. Port 110 is used by POP3 to receive e-mail messages. HTTP and port 443 is incorrect. HTTPS uses port 443, not HTTP."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following security controls is designed to prevent tailgating?",
    "options": [
      "Separation of duties",
      "Least privilege",
      "Mantrap",
      "Multifactor authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Mantrap is correct. A mantrap—an area between two locked doors, where the second door cannot be opened until the first door is locked—is designed to allow only one person at a time to enter a facility, effectively preventing tailgating. Note that mantraps are covered as “access control vestibules” in the Security+ objectives so watch for that on the real exam. Incorrect answers: Separation of duties is incorrect. Separation of duties is a security principal designed to prevent fraudulent activity within a business. Least privilege is incorrect. The principle of least privilege is designed to prevent someone from having more privileges than needed to perform their job. Multifactor authentication is incorrect. Multifactor authentication is designed to positively identify and authenticate an individual but does not prevent tailgating."
  },
  {
    "question": "A technician would like to employ the existing PKI infrastructure with the new wireless network. Which wireless security options require the use of PKI certificates?",
    "options": [
      "WEP",
      "WPA2 PSK",
      "WPA PSK",
      "EAP-TLS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: EAP-TLS is correct. EAP-TLS (Extensible Authentication Protocol – Transport Layer Security) can use PKI certificates to secure communications. Incorrect answers: WEP is incorrect. WEP (Wired Equivalent Privacy) is a deprecated Wi-Fi security protocol that does not use PKI certificates. WPA PSK is incorrect. Wi-Fi Protected Access (WPA) with pre-shared keys (PSK) does not use PKI; the pre-shared key is a passphrase. WPA2 PSK is incorrect. WPA2 PSK, like WPA PSK, uses a passphrase to secure the wireless network, not PKI certificates."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are investigating an incident involving one of your employees and want to ensure that they do not delete e-mail messages that can be used for evidence. What can you do to prevent the deletion of e-mail messages?",
    "options": [
      "Application approve list",
      "Legal hold",
      "Hashing",
      "Order of volatility"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Legal hold is correct. Putting a legal hold in place prevents the deletion of data and is a common feature of software such as e-mail. Incorrect answers: Application approve list is incorrect. You would not put an application on an approve list to solve this problem. Hashing is incorrect. Hashing would not help in this case, as it does not prevent data from being deleted. Order of volatility is incorrect. Although order of volatility is important to computer forensics, it does not prevent the deletion of e-mail."
  },
  {
    "question": "Leslie is projecting timelines to complete various analysis reports. Which list presents the correct order in which each analysis should be performed?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact, risk",
      "Risk, threat",
      "Threat, risk",
      "Threat, vulnerability"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Threat and risk is correct. Threat analysis identifies how vulnerable a party is to specific threats, the likelihood of those threats occurring, and their impact. Because a risk assessment relies on organizing threats to maximize potential opportunity, it cannot be conducted before a threat assessment. Incorrect answers: Risk and threat, Threat and vulnerability, and Business impact and risk are incorrect. These do not reflect the correct order in which to perform the listed analyses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following goals of information security deals with identifying modifications to data?",
    "options": [
      "Confidentiality",
      "Nonrepudiation",
      "Availability",
      "Integrity"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Integrityis correct. Integrity provides for detection of data modification. Incorrect answers: Confidentiality is incorrect. Confidentiality deals with protecting data from unauthorized access, not modification. Availability is incorrect. Availability ensures data and systems are available to authorized users whenever needed. Nonrepudiation is incorrect. Nonrepudiation involves preventing a user from denying that they performed an action."
  },
  {
    "question": "You must secure a corporate wireless router. All wireless traffic must be encrypted and all connecting devices must be centrally authenticated. Which security mechanism will accomplish this?",
    "options": [
      "WEP",
      "WPA PSK",
      "WPA2 PSK",
      "802.1x"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 802.1x is correct. The 802.1x standard requires device authentication and encrypts network traffic. For example, connected wireless devices could each have a unique PKI certificate that the wireless router validates against a centralized authentication server before allowing encrypted network access. Incorrect answers: WEP, WPA PSK, and WPA2 PSK are incorrect. The WEP and WPA PSK wireless security standards do not require centralized authentication; all that is required to connect to the network is the correct passphrase or key."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are modifying the backup schedule for the thirteen Windows and seven Unix servers in your server room. Full backups will occur Saturdays at 9:00 A.M. and incremental backups will occur every weekday starting at 7:00 P.M. Each server contains an average of 400GB of data. Backup tapes are stored in a safe down the hall in the IT manager's office. What problems exist with this scenario?",
    "options": [
      "Incremental backups must be used with differential backups.",
      "Backup tapes should be stored offsite.",
      "Differential backups can be used only with full backups.",
      "There is not enough time to perform incremental backups if the start time is 7:00 P.M."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Backup tapes should be stored offsite is correct. Backup tapes (or a verified copy of them) must be stored at an alternate location in case of fire or flood damage, to name just a few possibilities. Organizational data files as well as virtual machine snapshots are often stored on backup media, including in the cloud. Incorrect answers: Incremental backups must be used with differential backups, There is not enough time to perform incremental backups if the start time is 7:00 P.M, and Differential backups can be used only with full backups are incorrect. Incremental backups work with full backups just as differential backups do, but they should not be used together. In the scenario, we are not given specifics as to backup speeds, but given that incremental backups are being used for a relatively small amount of data, there should be plenty of time for the backups to complete."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements bests describes a Trusted Platform Module?",
    "options": [
      "A code module that performs authentication",
      "A software module that prevents application attacks",
      "A hardware module that performs cryptographic functions",
      "A secure logon module"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: A hardware module that performs cryptographic functions is correct. A Trusted Platform Module (TPM) is a hardware device, usually in the form of an embedded chip, that performs cryptographic functions, such as encrypting an entire hard drive. Incorrect answers: A software module that prevents application attacks is incorrect. A TPM module is not a software module that prevents application attacks. A code module that performs authentication is incorrect. A TPM module is not a code module that performs authentication. A secure logon module is incorrect. A TPM module is not a secure logon module."
  },
  {
    "question": "A router has two interfaces named E0 and E1. E0 connects to the Internet and has an IP address of 211.1.1.1/24. E1 connects to an LAN and has an IP address of 172.16.45.88/16. The administrator uses either SSH at TCP port 2222 or the address http://172.16.45.88 to administer the router. The router is configured with a complex password. What can be done to further secure this router?",
    "options": [
      "Disable SSH and enable Telnet.",
      "Configure SSH to use TCP port 22.",
      "Change the subnet mask of interface E1 to /24.",
      "Configure an SSL certificate for the web administration address."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Configure an SSL certificate for the web administration address is correct. HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure) should be configured with a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificate to secure the web administration of the router. Incorrect answers: Disable SSH and enable Telnet is incorrect. SSH (Secure Shell) is considered a more secure remote administration tool than Telnet because it encrypts the connection. Configure SSH to use TCP port 22 is incorrect. SSH already uses TCP port 22 by default. Change the subnet mask of interface E1 to /24 is incorrect. There is nothing wrong with the subnet mask of /16 for interface E1."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following methods is used to ensure data integrity?",
    "options": [
      "Authentication",
      "Signing",
      "Encryption",
      "Hashing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Hashing is correct. Hashing is used to ensure integrity by using an algorithm to obtain a fixed-length digest of a message or data. Hashes obtained both before and after data transmission must match in order to ensure integrity. Incorrect answers: Encryption is incorrect. Encryption ensures confidentiality. Signing is incorrect. Signing can help provide for nonrepudiation. Authentication is incorrect. Authentication means that an individual or entity has had their identity confirmed."
  },
  {
    "question": "A hacker has compromised your web server and triggered an alarm when they opened the password.txt file that you placed on the desktop. What deception technique best describes how your company detected the attack?",
    "options": [
      "DNS sinkhole",
      "Honeyfile",
      "Honeynet",
      "Honeypot"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Honeyfile is correct. A honeyfile is a document placed on a system that, when accessed, will trigger alarms. Incorrect Answers: Honeypot is incorrect. A honeypot is a system that is set up to lure the attacker to that system. It will have security protections in place to make it hard for the hacker, but also will log all activity to track what the attacker is doing. DNS sinkhole is incorrect. A DNS sinkhole is when the DNS server responds with fake IP address information for known-malicious URLs or domain names. These fake IP addresses are sent to the clients so that the clients do not connect to known-malicious sites. Honeynet is incorrect. A honeynet is an entire fake network set up to lure an attacker so that the hacker can be detected before they reach production systems."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are configuring a remote connection for a user workstation. You must select an authentication protocol to complete the configuration. Which choice would be the most secure?",
    "options": [
      "CHAP",
      "EAP-TLS",
      "PAP",
      "MD5"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: EAP-TLS is correct. Extensible Authentication Protocol – Transport Layer Security (EAP-TLS) requires both the server and client to possess a PKI certificate from a common trusted ancestor. Incorrect answers: PAP is incorrect. Password Authentication Protocol (PAP) sends credentials across the network in clear text. CHAP is incorrect. Challenge Handshake Authentication Protocol (CHAP) hashes credentials on each side of a connection and compares the results to determine whether authentication is successful or not. MD5 is incorrect. Message Digest 5 is not an authentication protocol; it is a hashing protocol."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have investigated a security incident involving users installing a free game downloaded from the Internet onto their desktop computers, only to find that the game is a virus. What could you do to prevent the users from installing and running the game?",
    "options": [
      "MDM",
      "Playbook",
      "Application deny list",
      "DLP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Application deny list is correct. You could put the game on the application deny list to prevent it from running on systems. Incorrect Answers: MDM is incorrect. Mobile device management (MDM) solutions are used to control features on mobile devices. DLP is incorrect. Data loss prevention (DLP) solutions are used to prevent someone from copying sensitive files without authorization. Playbook is incorrect. SOAR playbooks are used to automate responses to security incidents and contain a list of actions that should be taken when a security incident occurs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your NIDS alerts you of excessive network traffic spreading through each of your five VLANs. The problem seems to stem from malicious software that keeps replicating itself across the network. You react according to your incident response plan by turning off the affected switches. What caused the problem?",
    "options": [
      "Worm",
      "Trojan",
      "Fileless virus",
      "Spyware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Worm is correct. Worms are self-replicating malware that can consume network bandwidth, resulting in an unusable network. Virus scanners can detect known worm patterns. Inline network-based intrusion and detection systems (NIDs) examine network traffic as it traverses the network as opposed to stored captures (passive or offline). Incorrect Answers: Trojan is incorrect. Trojans are not self-replicating; they are malware that appear benign. Fileless virus is incorrect. A fileless virus loads malicious code directly into memory, thus never writing to the host file system. It does not replicate itself. Spyware is incorrect. Spyware monitors user activity and data without user consent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Chandra is a software developer. She has just completed a web application for a hardened e-commerce web site. What should be done before the application goes live?",
    "options": [
      "Ping the web site to ensure it is functional.",
      "Patch the web server.",
      "Test the PKI code in the web application.",
      "Use security fuzzing."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Use security fuzzing is correct. Security fuzzing is a process by which sample data is passed to the application to test its security and functionality. Incorrect answers: Test the PKI code in the web application is incorrect. PKI is a function of the web server, not the web application. Patch the web server is incorrect. Patching is not required; the question states the web server is already hardened. Ping the web site to ensure it is functional is incorrect. Pinging the web site is only relevant when testing connectivity, not the actual application itself."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a technique used to execute malicious code, to social-engineer unsuspecting users, or just to generally annoy a user?",
    "options": [
      "Pop-ups",
      "Static HTML code",
      "Tabbed browsing",
      "Certificate warnings"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Pop-ups is correct. Pop-ups are windows that appear during a browser session. They can execute malicious code or can be used to trick users into inputting private information. At best, they can also be very annoying. Incorrect answers: Certificate warnings is incorrect. Certificate warnings may be annoying to users, but they serve to alert them of expired or invalid server certificates. Tabbed browsing is incorrect. Tabbed browsing is touted as a convenience feature in most modern browsers and is typically not a security risk by itself. Static HTML code is incorrect. Static HTML code is generally the safest kind of code on a web site because it does not usually execute any client-side scripts."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following algorithms produces a 128-bit hash?",
    "options": [
      "3DES",
      "SHA-1",
      "MD5",
      "AES"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: MD5 is correct. MD5 (Message Digest version 5) produces a 128-bit hash. Incorrect answers: SHA-1 is incorrect. SHA-1 produces a 160-bit hash. AES is incorrect. AES is not a hashing algorithm; it is a symmetric encryption algorithm. 3DES is incorrect. 3DES is not a hashing algorithm; it is a symmetric encryption algorithm."
  },
  {
    "question": "A retail salesclerk is not allowed to maintain related bookkeeping records for accounting purposes. Which security principle does this apply to?",
    "options": [
      "Least privilege",
      "Due diligence",
      "Separation of duties",
      "Job rotation"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Separation of duties is correct. To reduce the possibility of fraud, no single business task and its bookkeeping should be performed by a single person. Incorrect answers: Due diligence is incorrect. Due diligence, for example, involves analyzing documentation prior to committing to a business or legal relationship. Least privilege is incorrect. Least privilege ensures that employees have only the rights needed to perform their job duties. Job rotation is incorrect. Job rotation exposes employees to different facets of the business."
  },
  {
    "question": "You would like to use caching to optimize the amount of HTTP and HTTPS network traffic to the Internet from your internal network. Which solution should you use?",
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "Proxy server",
      "Packet filtering firewall",
      "NAT"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Proxy server is correct. Not only does a proxy server retrieve Internet content on behalf of users, but it can also cache requested content so that subsequent requests can be satisfied locally from cache rather than from the Internet, thus reducing Internet traffic. Incorrect answers: NAT is incorrect. NAT is designed to allow outbound access using a single public IP address of the NAT device. Packet filtering firewall is incorrect. A packet filtering firewall allows or denies traffic based on protocol or address information. VPN is incorrect. A VPN allows secure access to a LAN across the Internet."
  },
  {
    "question": "James, a programmer, drives through downtown Vancouver and uses his laptop with a high-gain antenna to detect wireless networks. Which term best describes this activity?",
    "options": [
      "Rogue access point",
      "War driving",
      "Bluesnarfing",
      "War chalking"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: War driving is correct. War driving entails searching for wireless networks while moving—for example, while driving or riding a bus. Incorrect answers: Rogue access point is incorrect. Rogue access points are wireless access points added to a network without proper authorization; an unsecure rogue access point could compromise your entire network. War chalking is incorrect. War chalking entails documenting or charting open wireless networks. It originally meant charting open wireless networks by writing on sidewalks near the open network. Bluesnarfing is incorrect. Bluesnarfing is the unauthorized accessing of data through a Bluetooth wireless connection."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of tool is commonly used to automate incident response?",
    "options": [
      "MDM",
      "PKI",
      "SOAR",
      "SIEM"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SOAR is correct. Security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR) solutions use runbooks to automate incident response thus reducing incident response time. Incorrect answers: SIEM is incorrect. Security information and event management (SIEM) tools are used to centrally collect log data related to IT activity that can then be analyzed for potential security incidents. MDM is incorrect. Mobile device management (MDM) solutions are used to centrally manage the configuration of mobile devices in the enterprise. PKI is incorrect. Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) is a hierarchy of digital security certificates."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are performing a security assessment of the network and would like to send output to a system where you have set up a custom port for the system to receive the data on. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "Netcat",
      "ifconfig",
      "nmap",
      "arp"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Netcat is correct. Netcat can be used to set up a listening port on a system that you can then use to send data to. Incorrect answers: nmap is incorrect. nmap is a port scanner used to discover ports and services that are running on a system. arp is incorrect. arp is a tool used to view the ARP cache on a system. The ARP cache contains a list of IP addresses and corresponding MAC addresses of systems you have communicated with recently. ifconfig is incorrect. ifconfig is a Linux command to view and modify the IP address of a Linux system."
  },
  {
    "question": "A Linux firewall administrator creates a rule allowing inbound packets from 148.34.99.17 destined for TCP port 22 on 206.2.4.45. Which of the following statements regarding this firewall rule are true, assuming default ports are in use? (Choose three.)",
    "options": [
      "The rule applies to layer 6 of the OSI model.",
      "The rule allows SSH administration of 206.2.4.45.",
      "Successful connections from 148.34.99.17 to 206.2.4.45 will be encrypted.",
      "The rule applies to layer 4 of the OSI model."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      2,
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: The rule allows SSH administration of 206.2.4.45, Successful connections from 148.34.99.17 to 206.2.4.45 will be encrypted, and The rule applies to layer 4 of the OSI model are correct. SSH by default uses TCP port 22 to allow encrypted connections for remote administration from 148.34.99.17 targeted to the SSH host at 206.2.4.45. Port numbers apply to layer 4 (Transport) of the OSI model. Incorrect answer: The rule applies to layer 6 of the OSI model is incorrect. The firewall access control list (ACL) rule does not apply to layer 6 (Presentation) of the OSI model. This layer is concerned with how data is presented (for example, between different character sets) to the next highest layer, layer 7 (Application)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Administrators who grant access to resources by assigning users to job roles and then assigning the job role permissions is known as which type of access control model?",
    "options": [
      "Mandatory access control",
      "Rule-based access control",
      "Discretionary access control",
      "Role-based access control"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Role-based access control is correct. Role-based access control grants access to groups performing specific functions, or roles, but not to individuals. Incorrect answers: Discretionary access control is incorrect. Discretionary access control allows data owners/creators to grant access to individuals or groups. Mandatory access control is incorrect. Mandatory access control permits only administrators to grant access based on security labels. Rule-based access control is incorrect. Rule-based access control grants access to resources based on specific rules associated with the resource."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a removable USB drive is lost, which of the following protection mechanisms could help prevent data loss or disclosure?",
    "options": [
      "Remote wipe",
      "Encryption",
      "Permissions",
      "Strong authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Encryption is correct. Encryption can protect data stored on removable media such as USB drives in the event the media is lost or stolen. This would prevent an unauthorized user from accessing the data. Incorrect answers: Permissions is incorrect. Permissions would not help prevent data loss or disclosure, as they typically apply only to removable media that is connected to the system managing the permissions. Permissions can easily be changed or removed from removable media. Strong authentication is incorrect. Strong authentication would be ineffective because the authentication mechanism typically is not on the media itself, but on the system it is connected to. Remote wipe is incorrect. Remote wipe is used to remotely erase data from drives in wireless devices. A USB or other removable media would not support this technology."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are considered symmetric encryption algorithms? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "SHA",
      "3DES",
      "AES",
      "MD5",
      "RSA"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: AES and 3DES are correct. AES and 3DES are considered encryption standards and use symmetric algorithms. Incorrect answers: SHA is incorrect. SHA is a hashing algorithm, not a symmetric encryption algorithm. RSA is incorrect. RSA is an asymmetric encryption algorithm. MD5 is incorrect. MD5 is a hashing algorithm."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are potential application security issues requiring attention except which one?",
    "options": [
      "SQL injection",
      "Buffer overflows",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Malware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Malware is correct. Malware is a security issue, but not specific to any applications. Incorrect answers: Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting is a web-based attack where a client-side script is sent to a web server with the intent of the script being sent to and executing on another client's host or web browser. SQL injection is incorrect. In SQL injection attacks, the hacker uses SQL commands that are executing behind the scenes in order to manipulate the data in a database. Buffer overflows is incorrect. Buffer overflow attacks target memory usage in programs."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are asked to configure network security appliances to detect abnormal activities that could indicate a network attack or worm. What must you first do?",
    "options": [
      "Establish a configuration schedule.",
      "Patch the network appliances.",
      "Establish a network baseline.",
      "Patch the operating system."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Establish a network baseline is correct. Abnormal network activity cannot accurately be determined if there is no baseline, or benchmark, of normal network activity on a particular network. Incorrect answers: Patch the network appliances, Patch the operating system, and Establish a configuration schedule are incorrect. Patching and setting configuration schedules are not the first things that should be done when you want to detect abnormal activity. These are hardening activities."
  },
  {
    "question": "During which incident response phase would a malware outbreak be limited in order not to infect other devices?",
    "options": [
      "Containment",
      "Eradication",
      "Recovery",
      "Identification"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Containment is correct. Containment relates to a malware outbreak not being spread and may involve activities such as disconnecting infected hosts from all wired and wireless networks. Incorrect answers: Identification is incorrect. Incident identification establishes that an incident has indeed occurred, whether identification is done manually or through automated SIEM solutions. Eradication is incorrect. Eradication involves removal of any tools the attacker used and may include tools such as antimalware to remove the infection from devices. Recovery is incorrect. Recovery involves returning a system or data to its previous functional state, such as restoring data backups after a ransomware infection."
  },
  {
    "question": "Under what circumstance might a risk be acceptable? (Choose the best answer.)",
    "options": [
      "The ALE is less than the cost of mitigating the risk.",
      "The SLE is less than the cost of mitigating the risk.",
      "The ARO is less than the cost of mitigating the risk.",
      "The ALE is more than the cost of mitigating the risk."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: The ALE is less than the cost of mitigating the risk is correct. ALE (annual loss expectancy) is a dollar figure derived from the SLE (single loss expectancy) and the ARO (annual rate of occurrence). For example, the probability of an e-mail server being down for four hours a year might be 65 percent, at a loss of $900, due to the unavailability of that e-mail server for four hours. ALE = ARO × SLE = 65% × $900; therefore, the ALE value would be $585. So, for example, paying $700 annually to protect against a $585 ALE value cannot be justified. Incorrect answers: The ALE is more than the cost of mitigating the risk is incorrect. If the ALE is more than the cost of mitigating the risk, mitigating the risk would be considered acceptable, because mitigating the risk would cost the business less money than having the risk materialize. The SLE is less than the cost of mitigating the risk and The ARO is less than the cost of mitigating the risk are incorrect. The SLE and ARO should not be considered by themselves in this scenario because they are both used to derive the ALE."
  },
  {
    "question": "To increase response time to your public web site, you decide to purchase three network load-balancing appliances to match your three web servers. Your web site is registered with the name www.faroutwidets.com using IP address 216.76.0.55. What IP addresses should the public interface of each load balancer assume?",
    "options": [
      "216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.56, 216.76.0.57",
      "216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.55",
      "216.76.0.52, 216.76.0.53, 216.76.0.54",
      "216.76.0.56, 216.76.0.57, 216.76.0.58"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.55 is correct. Network load balancers (NLBs) should accept client requests to the requested service (216.76.0.55); thus, they must all be configured to listen on the same virtual IP address. Incoming client requests are then distributed to the least busy backend web servers. When multiple load balancers are used, active/active configurations mean all load balancers are active simultaneously. Active/passive means only one load balancer is active; the passive node becomes active when the active node goes down. Incorrect answers: 216.76.0.56, 216.76.0.57, 216.76.0.58, 216.76.0.52, 216.76.0.53, 216.76.0.54, and 216.76.0.55, 216.76.0.56, 216.76.0.57 are incorrect. These addresses should not be used; 216.76.0.55 should be used for all three NLB public interfaces."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager has asked that you create a forensics image of an employee's hard drive. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "FTK Imager",
      "Nessus",
      "Autopsy",
      "WinHex"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: FTK Imager is correct. FTK Imager is a free tool you can use to create an image of a drive or an image of memory. Incorrect answers: WinHex is incorrect. WinHex is a hex editor that can be used to view the raw hex data on a file. Autopsy is incorrect. Autopsy is a forensics analysis tool that can be used to analyze an image after it has been created with FTK Imager or dd. Nessus is incorrect. Nessus is a vulnerability scanner."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered potential cloud computing security issues except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Legal issues",
      "Security management",
      "Hardware footprint",
      "Many customers sharing service"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Hardware footprint is correct. A reduced hardware footprint is possible when using cloud computing, which can save equipment and operating costs. Incorrect answers: Security management is incorrect. Security management could be a potential issue of moving to the cloud. Legal issues is incorrect. Legal issues surrounding what laws govern the data could be a concern with moving to the cloud. This issue is known as data sovereignty. Many customers sharing service is incorrect. An organization may have issues with the fact that many customers are sharing the same service or servers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Examine the exhibit. Which of the following statements are true regarding this firewall rule set? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Access to SSL-enabled web sites is blocked.",
      "The ability to Ping external hosts is blocked.",
      "195.22.35.16 is a TFTP server.",
      "195.22.35.16 is a DNS server."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: The ability to Ping external hosts is blocked and 195.22.35.16 is a DNS server are correct. Ping uses ICMP (Internet Control Message Protocol), and this is implicitly blocked by the last rule. 195.22.35.16 is a Domain Name System (DNS) server, because DNS servers listen for client requests on UDP port 53. Incorrect answers: Access to SSL-enabled web sites is blocked is incorrect. SSL web sites listen on TCP port 443, and the rules allow this type of traffic. 195.22.35.16 is a TFTP server is incorrect. TFTP (Trivial File Transfer Protocol) servers use UDP port 69, not 53."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of malware is triggered by a condition or date?",
    "options": [
      "Spyware",
      "Dateware",
      "Conditionware",
      "Logic bomb"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Logic bomb is correct. A logic bomb waits until a specific condition is met (for example, a date) before the code runs. Incorrect Answers: Dateware is incorrect. Dateware is not a type of malware. Spyware is incorrect. Spyware monitors user activity without user consent. Conditionware is incorrect. Conditionware is not a type of malware."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a listing of systems or persons authorized to access an asset such as a network or file?",
    "options": [
      "Access control list",
      "Hosts file",
      "Ruleset",
      "Policy"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Access control list is correct. An access control list (ACL) is a listing of systems or persons authorized to access a resource. Incorrect answers: Ruleset is incorrect. A ruleset is typically found on a security device such as a firewall and contains connection rules and filters for the network. Policy is incorrect. A policy might mandate that an access control list must exist but will usually not specify the entities or resources on it. Hosts file is incorrect. The hosts file is a file on a machine that provides fully qualified domain name or hostname resolution to IP addresses in the absence of DNS."
  },
  {
    "question": "What potential benefits does a penetration test provide? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Identifying vulnerabilities",
      "Preventing financial loss",
      "Reducing single points of failure",
      "Identifying wasted IPv4 addresses"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Identifying vulnerabilities and Preventing financial loss are correct. Penetration tests are conducted to identify vulnerabilities and to prevent financial loss due to those intrusions. For example, financial loss can be incurred through the theft of trade secrets or shattered public, investor, and customer faith. Incorrect answers: Reducing single points of failure and Identifying wasted IPv4 addresses are incorrect. These are not penetration testing considerations."
  },
  {
    "question": "Unused switch ports are disabled on your Ethernet switches. You are asked to ensure that only the appropriate employee computers can be used when plugged into Ethernet wall jacks in employee cubicles. How can this be accomplished?",
    "options": [
      "Configure each switch port to allow a specific MAC address.",
      "Configure each switch port to allow a specific UDP port address.",
      "Configure each switch port to allow a specific TCP port address.",
      "Configure each switch port to allow a specific IP address."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Configure each switch port to allow a specific MAC address is correct. Configure each switch port to allow the specific MAC address for the employee computer that will be connecting to that switch port. Switches that examine MAC addresses are called layer 2 switches; switches with built-in IP functionality are called layer 3 switches. Network bridges are also layer 2 devices. Incorrect answers: Configure each switch port to allow a specific IP address is incorrect. The MAC address is less likely to change on a computer (as that's hard coded on the NIC and would typically change only when a NIC changed) than its IP address. Configure each switch port to allow a specific TCP port address and Configure each switch port to allow a specific UDP port address are incorrect. TCP and UDP port numbers do not uniquely identify a computer. Also, layer 2 devices, such as switches, don't have a context of ports so they wouldn't be able to perform this operation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are considered benefits of server virtualization? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Efficient application of software updates",
      "Faster network access",
      "Centralized data storage",
      "Cheaper software licensing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Efficient application of software updates and Centralized data storage are correct. Because virtualized servers could be running on the same physical host, patch deployment is efficient. Virtualized servers often use shared disk storage, thus centralizing data and making backups quicker and easier. Incorrect answers: Faster network access is incorrect. Virtualized servers are not faster than physical servers, although their deployment often is. Virtual machine sprawl results from the ease of deploying virtual machines and forgetting about them over time as their use declines. Cheaper software licensing is incorrect. Licensing for virtualized servers is not always cheaper than it is for physical hosts."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are performing an internal computer forensics investigation. You have seized the phone, laptop, and desktop PC of one of the employees in the company. What is the first thing you should complete after seizing the evidence?",
    "options": [
      "Containment",
      "Tabletop exercise",
      "Order of volatility",
      "Chain of custody"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Chain of custody is correct. You should fill out and maintain a chain of custody document for each piece of evidence that is seized. Incorrect answers: Containment is incorrect. Containment is the act of a first responder when dealing with incident response, not computer forensics. Tabletop exercise is incorrect. A tabletop exercise is a method of testing incident response procedures. Order of volatility is incorrect. Order of volatility represents the order in which evidence should be collected."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are valid types of Windows event logs except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Security",
      "Process",
      "System",
      "Application"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Process is correct. There is no specific process type of log, although processes can be logged in Windows and usually appear in one of the other log types. Incorrect answers: System is incorrect. The system log contains general information about the system, such as when the print queue has been purged, device driver issues, and services that failed to start. Application is incorrect. The application log contains information about applications running on the system. Security is incorrect. The security log contain information on security events such as a user failing to log on."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which security role addresses who controls access to data?",
    "options": [
      "Data owner",
      "Custodian",
      "Server administrator",
      "End user"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Data owner is correct. Data owners determine which access rights certain parties have to information. Incorrect answers: Custodian, Server administrator, and End user are incorrect. Custodians are responsible for maintaining and protecting data, much as a server administrator would. End users simply use data they have been given access to."
  },
  {
    "question": "A company server is used to store sensitive trade secrets and design plans. A port scan shows services listening on TCP ports 80 and 25. Server log files reveal no activity for these ports since the server upgrade project three years ago. What can you do to harden this server, assuming default ports are being used? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Generate file hashes for the design plans.",
      "Apply operating system patches.",
      "Disable the web and mail servers.",
      "Store sensitive files on a different server."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Apply operating system patches and Disable the web and mail servers are correct. Patching an OS is always a critical hardening procedure for devices and software that have not yet reached end-of-life, although some embedded devices do not support firmware patching. Patches can be applied to individual devices or from a centralized configuration tool such as Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM). Since the web server (port 80) and mail server (port 25) have not been used in three years, they should be disabled to reduce the attack surface. Incorrect answers: Store sensitive files on a different server is incorrect. There is no indication that any other server would be better suited to store sensitive data if the current server is hardened. Generate file hashes for the design plans is incorrect. File hashes reveal any file modifications but do not protect the confidentiality of the files."
  },
  {
    "question": "A malicious user uses an Internet chat room to issue commands to 700 compromised computers around the world. The zombies are instructed to execute a smurf attack against a web site. What type of attack is this?",
    "options": [
      "Distributed cracker",
      "Exploitation framework",
      "Distributed denial of service",
      "Distributed Gargamel-ElGamel attack"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Distributed denial of service is correct. Distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks flood victim networks with traffic in an attempt to prevent legitimate service access. Using a botnet to execute a smurf attack does just this. Incorrect Answer: Exploitation framework is incorrect. Exploitation frameworks are toolsets designed to identify and exploit vulnerabilities in hardware and software systems. Distributed cracker is incorrect. There is no such thing as a distributed cracker, although tools such as password crackers do exist. Distributed Gargamel-ElGamel attack is incorrect. There is no such thing as a distributed Gargamel-ElGamel attack."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are classes of controls except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Inhibitive",
      "Detective",
      "Preventative",
      "Corrective"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Inhibitive is correct. There is no inhibitive control class. Incorrect answers: Preventative is incorrect. Preventative controls are a type of security control. Corrective is incorrect. Corrective controls are a type of security control. Detective is incorrect. Detective controls are a type of security control."
  },
  {
    "question": "In which order should the following items be conducted?",
    "options": [
      "ALE, business analysis, risk analysis",
      "Business impact analysis, ALE, risk analysis",
      "Risk analysis, ALE, business impact analysis",
      "ALE, risk analysis, business impact analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: ALE, risk analysis, business impact analysis is correct. The ALE is a dollar figure used in quantitative risk analysis to prioritize risks; therefore, it cannot be calculated after a risk analysis. The business impact analysis can occur only after risks have been identified. Incorrect answers: Risk analysis, ALE, business impact analysis, Business impact analysis, ALE, risk analysis, and ALE, business analysis, risk analysis are incorrect. The process must begin with ALE, followed by a risk analysis and then a business impact analysis."
  },
  {
    "question": "Social engineering breaches which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Authority",
      "Intimidation",
      "Trust",
      "Familiarity"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Trust is correct. Social engineering is a breach of trust in which victims are lured into trusting the validity of the person or company they are in communication with. Incorrect Answers: Intimidation is incorrect. Intimidation is not breached; it is a tactic used by malicious users. Victims could be intimidated into paying an urgent fine imposed by a figure of authority, such as by a fake law enforcement message. Familiarity is incorrect. Familiarity is not breached; familiarity with a company logo or a salesperson could easily be spoofed. Authority is incorrect. Social engineering breaches trust, not authority."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are a web developer. Some customers report links on your web pages to unrelated offerings of various products. As the web developer, you check your web site code and verify that these links are not coded into your web pages. What can you tell your customers was the most likely reason for this?",
    "options": [
      "The customers' computers are infected with a fileless virus.",
      "The customers' computers are infected with a Trojan.",
      "The customers' computers are infected with adware.",
      "The customers' computers are infected with a worm."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: The customers' computers are infected with adware is correct. Adware could add links to web pages your customers visit for products and services they may want based on their computer usage patterns. Adware is often the result of spyware that monitors a user's computing activity such as web searches. Incorrect Answers: The customers' computers are infected with a fileless virus is incorrect. A fileless virus loads malicious code directly into memory, thus never writing to the host file system. This would not redirect users to specific ads. The customers' computers are infected with a worm is incorrect. Worms are self-replicating malware. This would not redirect users to specific ads. The customers' computers are infected with a Trojan is incorrect. Trojans are malware that appear benign. This would not redirect users to specific ads."
  },
  {
    "question": "Rachelle is a server administrator. During her required monthly server maintenance duties, Rachelle clears all server logs to increase usable disk space. Her job also requires her to create user accounts and grant permissions to network shared folders and printers. What is the security violation in this scenario?",
    "options": [
      "Incident management",
      "Least privilege",
      "Separation of duties",
      "Acceptable use"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Separation of duties is correct. Rachelle is a server administrator, and she has the ability to erase all server logs—the potential exists for Rachelle to abuse server administrative privileges and clear any audit trails. Incorrect answers: Least privilege is incorrect. Least privilege ensures that users have only the rights they need. Acceptable use is incorrect. Acceptable use policies state how employees are to use corporate assets properly. Incident management is incorrect. Incident management is a structured approach to handling incidents. None of these items is violated in the example."
  },
  {
    "question": "What purpose does data labeling serve in a computing environment?",
    "options": [
      "It allows for quick retrieval of documents from filing cabinets.",
      "It makes finding spare hardware easier.",
      "It makes audit logs easier to read.",
      "It identifies the sensitivity level of digital data."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: It identifies the sensitivity level of digital data is correct. Data labeling identifies the sensitivity of digital data (the question asks about computing environments). Incorrect answers: It makes audit logs easier to read, It makes finding spare hardware easier, and It allows for quick retrieval of documents from filing cabinets are incorrect. Data labeling in computing environments does not make audit logs easy to read, nor does it make spare hardware easier to find or documents quick to retrieve from filing cabinets."
  },
  {
    "question": "You must distribute the network traffic among a collection of mirrored servers. Which device should you use?",
    "options": [
      "NAT",
      "Proxy server",
      "Load mirror",
      "Load balancer"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Load balancer is correct. Load balancers attempt to distribute network traffic evenly to a collection of hosts. Unlike DNS round robin configurations to distribute network traffic, load balancers can detect unavailable hosts and prevent traffic from being sent to them. Incorrect answer: Proxy server is incorrect. Proxy servers retrieve Internet content on behalf of users, but they cannot balance network traffic workloads. Load mirror is incorrect. Load mirror is a fictitious term. NAT is incorrect. NAT (Network Address Translation) does not control network traffic; it enables a single public IP address to be used for many internal computers connecting externally."
  },
  {
    "question": "An employee signs a document stating that company e-mail may be used only to conduct business; personal messages are forbidden. What type of policy is this?",
    "options": [
      "Storage retention",
      "E-mail retention",
      "Disaster recovery",
      "Acceptable use"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Acceptable use is correct. A document stating how company assets can and cannot be used is an acceptable use policy. Incorrect answers: Disaster recovery is incorrect. A disaster recovery policy outlines which parties should perform which tasks in the event of a disaster. E-mail retention is incorrect. An e-mail retention policy determines how long e-mail messages must be kept and how they are to be kept. Storage retention is incorrect. A storage retention policy determines how any data stored digitally is to be kept and for how long."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has a salesperson who travels a lot and will be connecting to hotel networks. What security recommendation would you make for her laptop?",
    "options": [
      "Unencrypted drive",
      "FDE",
      "Null password",
      "Host-based firewall"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Host-based firewall is correct. A host-based firewall should be used when connecting to untrusted networks, such as one in a hotel. Incorrect answers: Unencrypted drive is incorrect. Having an unencrypted drive is not a security recommendation. Null password is incorrect. Having a null password (empty password, or password not set) is not a security recommendation. FDE is incorrect. Although full disk encryption (FDE) can help if the laptop is lost or stolen, it will not help you in situations where you are making connections to an unknown and potentially unsecure network. You could potentially be infected with a virus by connecting to an unknown network without having a firewall enabled, or you could be vulnerable to an attack."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack uses an application vulnerability in which a web page has code that references another site and the attack automatically uses the target's cookie data for authentication if the cookie is present and has not expired?",
    "options": [
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "SQL injection",
      "Cross-site request forgery",
      "Buffer overflow"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cross-site request forgery is correct. Cross-site request forgery (XSRF) is an attack that takes advantage of an application vulnerability in which a web page has code that references another site and automatically uses the target's cookie data for authentication if the cookie is present and has not expired. Incorrect answers: Buffer overflow is incorrect. Buffer overflow attacks target memory usage in programs. Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting attacks attempt to inject client-side code into a web page. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection attempts to insert SQL commands into an input field to gain information from a database."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are researching network vulnerability assessment tools to find one that can identify operating system–specific weaknesses. What type of tool should you use?",
    "options": [
      "Nmap",
      "Nessus",
      "Wireshark",
      "netstat"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Nessus is correct. Nessus is a vulnerability scanning tool that can not only identify hosts and open ports, but also identify software-specific weaknesses. Incorrect answers: netstat is incorrect. The netstat command is used to list Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and User Datagram Protocol (UDP) port information on a given host. Nmap is incorrect. Nmap is a network scanning tool that can identify hosts and open ports, but not operating system specific weaknesses. Wireshark is incorrect. Wireshark is used to capture and analyze network traffic; it is not a vulnerability scanning tool."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are designing the security for a hybrid cloud solution that is to be used by your company. What security solution would you use that allows you to create policies that control the type of traffic that is permitted to flow from your on-premises environment to the cloud?",
    "options": [
      "COPE",
      "CASB",
      "Replication",
      "Containers"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: CASB is correct. A cloud access security broker (CASB) is a security service that sits between your on-premises environment and your cloud provider's environment. The CASB allows you to define security policies that apply to network traffic flowing outside your current on-premises environment to the cloud. Incorrect answers: Containers is incorrect. Containers are a form of virtualization that, unlike a virtual machine, share the operating system kernel of the host system. Containers are used to host applications and separate the application from other applications running on the system. Replication is incorrect. Replication is a cloud feature that is used to ensure that data is available to the customer by copying the data to other regions within the cloud. COPE is incorrect. Corporate-owned, personally enabled (COPE) is a mobile device deployment model where the company supplies the device to the user. Because the company owns the device, it is managed by the IT department, but the company allows and promotes personal usage of the device as well."
  },
  {
    "question": "Brendon, one of the sales managers within your company, tries to visit www.facebook.com but is blocked from doing so. Brendon receives a message indicating that access to the site is not allowed. What type of security feature is being used to block Brendon from accessing the site?",
    "options": [
      "Access point",
      "Content filter",
      "Network address translation",
      "Firewall"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Content filter is correct. A content filter is a feature that is built into devices such as proxy servers, firewalls, and home routers that prevents users from accessing content such as a specific web site. Incorrect answers: Access point is incorrect. An access point allows wireless clients to connect to the network, and a firewall is used to control which traffic can enter or leave the network. Firewall is incorrect. Although the firewall may have content-filtering features, if “content filter” is listed as a choice, it is the more precise answer. Network address translation is incorrect. Network address translation (NAT) is a feature that hides internal addresses behind a public address."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following ports must be enabled on firewalls and other network security devices to permit L2TP-encrypted traffic through?",
    "options": [
      "1701",
      "443",
      "1723",
      "22"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 1701 is correct. UDP port 1701 is used for L2TP VPNs. Incorrect answers: 1723 is incorrect. Port 1723 is used by PPTP. 443 is incorrect. Port 443 is used by HTTPS. 22 is incorrect. Port 22 is used by SSH."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms describes an attack where the attacker disconnects one party in a communications session and assumes their identity for the remainder of the session?",
    "options": [
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Spoofing",
      "Impersonation",
      "Session hijacking"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Session hijacking is correct. Session hijacking is an attack that takes place by terminating one party to a communications session and assuming their identity for the session. This can happen during web-based application transactions. Incorrect answers: Impersonation is incorrect. Impersonation is a social engineering attack that involves pretending to be another person. Spoofing is incorrect. Spoofing means to use a false IP address, MAC address, or user identity. Spoofing can be confused with session hijacking, but spoofing may mean starting and ending the session while pretending to be another user or host. Session hijacking is different because of the interruption of the session and hijacking it from a legitimate user. Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting is a web-based attack where a client-side script is sent to a web server with the intent of the script being sent to and executing on another client's host or web browser."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is considered an intangible impact to an organization?",
    "options": [
      "Loss of production",
      "Employee safety",
      "Loss of customer confidence",
      "Loss of revenue"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Loss of customer confidence is correct. It is difficult to place a value on or measure customer confidence in the business, so it is considered an intangible loss. Incorrect answers: Loss of production is incorrect. Loss of production results in revenue loss and can be measured and assigned a dollar loss value. Loss of revenue is incorrect. Loss of revenue can be measured and assigned a loss value in dollars. Employee safety is incorrect. Employee safety can be measured in terms of time lost, cost of temporary replacement, medical costs, fines, and so forth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attack method targets weaknesses in WEP encryption keys?",
    "options": [
      "Plain-text attack",
      "Brute-force attack",
      "IV attack",
      "Birthday attack"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: IV attack is correct. An initialization vector (IV) attack takes advantage of the weak implementation of the 24-bit IVs in WEP, which has a relatively small keyspace and repeats the IV periodically. Incorrect answers: Birthday attack is incorrect. A birthday attack is a password attack. Plain-text attack is incorrect. A plain-text attack can be used to compare known plain text with cipher text to decrypt data and is not used to crack WEP keys. Brute-force attack is incorrect. A brute-force attack is used to crack complex passwords."
  },
  {
    "question": "What tool would you use during a penetration test to automate a scan of a system and identify vulnerabilities that exist on that system?",
    "options": [
      "Sn1per",
      "Metasploit",
      "netcat",
      "hping"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Sn1per is correct. Sn1per is a tool that automates a scan of a system and identifies vulnerabilities that exist on that system. Incorrect answers: Metasploit is incorrect. Metasploit is an exploitation framework that comes with a number of different exploits to attack different types of systems. hping is incorrect. hping is a ping program that allows you to customize the protocol used and the port used to perform the ping. netcat is incorrect. netcat is a program used to open a port on a system or connect to an open port on another system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements best describes a quantitative risk assessment?",
    "options": [
      "An assessment that assigns arbitrary weighted factors to threats, vulnerabilities, and exposures",
      "An assessment that uses dollar figures and calculates risk in terms of loss",
      "An assessment that uses subjective probability and impact values, such as high, medium, and low",
      "An assessment that uses statistical probabilities to calculate likelihood of risk"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: An assessment that uses dollar figures and calculates risk in terms of loss is correct. A quantitative risk assessment examines risk in terms of dollar loss to an organization. Incorrect answers: An assessment that assigns arbitrary weighted factors to threats, vulnerabilities, and exposures is incorrect. Assessments that use weighted factors is not a valid choice in this context. An assessment that uses statistical probabilities to calculate likelihood of risk is incorrect. Assessments that use statistical probabilities is not a valid choice in this context. An assessment that uses subjective probability and impact values, such as high, medium, and low is incorrect. A qualitative risk assessment is one that uses subjective probability and impact values, such as high, medium, and low."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term used when two different pieces of data generate the same hash value?",
    "options": [
      "Disruption",
      "Interference",
      "Collision",
      "Crossover error"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Collision is correct. A collision occurs when two pieces of plain text are hashed and produce identical hashes. Incorrect answers: Disruption is incorrect. Disruption is an invalid term in this context. Crossover error is incorrect. A crossover error is a reference to biometric authentication factors. Interference is incorrect. Interference is when a wireless signal is being disrupted by an object such as a microwave or cordless phone."
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to elastic IT services accessible over a network for which you pay based on usage?",
    "options": [
      "Web-based computing",
      "Server virtualization",
      "Remote desktop services",
      "Cloud computing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cloud computing is correct. Cloud computing removes the hardware and software cost and maintenance, normally in exchange for a fee based on resource usage. The use of physical server resources is provided by the cloud computing provider. Incorrect answers: Server virtualization is incorrect. Cloud computing uses server virtualization to host many cloud-based services, but virtualization alone does not define cloud computing. Remote desktop services is incorrect. Windows virtual machines can be remotely managed using Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP). Web-based computing is incorrect. Web-based computing is not a standard term for this scenario; it describes cloud computing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms is commonly used to describe a device that displays a random number for 30 to 60 seconds that is used along with a username and password in order to log on?",
    "options": [
      "Windows token",
      "Smart token",
      "Hardware token",
      "Logical token"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Hardware token is correct. A hardware token is a physical device that displays a random number for 30 to 60 seconds. The user enters that random number, along with their username and password, in order to log on. Incorrect answers: Smart token is incorrect. A smart token does not exist in this context. Logical token is incorrect. A logical token is generated at logon and contains the user SID, group SIDs, and the privileges of the user. A logical token is presented to any resource to determine if access to the resource should be granted. Windows token is incorrect. A Windows token is a logical token used by Windows networks to determine if someone should get access to a resource."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attack is used to inject commands inside an HTTP message with the goal of navigating to the operating system and executing system commands?",
    "options": [
      "SQL injection",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Directory traversal",
      "XML injection"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct Answer: Directory traversal is correct. A directory traversal attack enables a malicious user to inject commands inside the HTTP message in order to travel through the directory structure of the web server. After navigating backward in the directory structure, the hacker then moves forward into the operating system directory and tries to run operating system commands. Incorrect answers: Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting is a popular form of attack that involves the hacker inserting script code into a form on a web page and submitting the script code to the server so that it will then be sent to other clients. XML injection is incorrect. An XML injection attack is similar to an SQL injection, except that the hacker is inserting XML code into the application. SQL injection is incorrect. In SQL injection attacks, the hacker uses the SQL commands that are executing behind the scenes in order to manipulate the data in the database."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms is defined as something that can cause harm to an asset?",
    "options": [
      "Risk",
      "Vulnerability",
      "Loss",
      "Threat"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Threat is correct. A threat is defined as an entity or event that has the potential to cause harm or damage to an asset. A threat could cause the organization to suffer a financial loss. Incorrect answers: Risk is incorrect. Risk is the possibility that a threat could harm an asset. Vulnerability is incorrect. A vulnerability is a weakness in the system. Loss is incorrect. A loss is what damage occurs when a vulnerability is exploited by a threat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms is used to describe software or hardware that analyzes information leaving the organization to ensure that sensitive information is not being leaked?",
    "options": [
      "Encryption",
      "Data loss prevention",
      "Firewall",
      "Intrusion prevention system"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Data loss prevention is correct. Data loss prevention (DLP) is software or hardware that analyzes information leaving the organization to ensure that sensitive information is not being leaked. DLP can be implemented to monitor network traffic and to identify sensitive information being sent through instant messenger, e-mail, or protocols such as HTTP and FTP. DLP can also analyze data in storage to ensure sensitive information is not being stored in the wrong location. Incorrect answers: Firewall is incorrect. A firewall filters traffic coming into or exiting a network but does not inspect data to determine if it is sensitive. Encryption is incorrect. Encryption can protect sensitive data but cannot decide whether or not data is sensitive. Intrusion prevention system is incorrect. An intrusion prevention system can be used to prevent network attacks."
  },
  {
    "question": "The individual or group of individuals within an organization who can decrypt information in the event of a termination or loss of keys is usually which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Recovery agent",
      "Manager",
      "Law enforcement officer",
      "Administrator"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Recovery agent is correct. A recovery agent is usually assigned the specific task of recovering keys to decrypt information if a user leaves an organization or is terminated. Incorrect answers: Administrator is incorrect. The administrator cannot decrypt information when the owner's keys are missing unless the admin is made a recovery agent. Manager is incorrect. The manager cannot decrypt information when the owner's keys are missing unless the manager is made a recovery agent. Law enforcement officer is incorrect. A law enforcement officer cannot decrypt information when the owner's keys are missing unless the officer is made a recovery agent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Instead of allowing an application to crash, error and exception handling uses a technique to intercept the errors and to display friendly warning messages. This is known as which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Injection",
      "Input validation",
      "Tunneling",
      "Trapping"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Trapping is correct. Trapping an error means that instead of the error actually happening, the programmer intercepts the error and displays a friendly warning message. Incorrect answers: Injection is incorrect. Injection is a type of attack usually seen in SQL, XML, and other types of data. Input validation is incorrect. Input validation is the process of ensuring that inputs to a web form, for example, are valid and within bounds. Tunneling is incorrect. Tunneling is a method of securing data by encrypting it with one protocol and sending it over another."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a common authentication protocol that controls who gains access to a wired or wireless network by requiring the client to authenticate against a central authentication database such as a RADIUS server?",
    "options": [
      "PAP",
      "802.1X",
      "CHAP",
      "Kerberos"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 802.1X is correct. The 802.1X protocol is a newer authentication protocol, primarily used in wireless networking, that offers both encryption and mutual authentication. Incorrect answers: Kerberos is incorrect. Kerberos is not used for wireless authentication. CHAP is incorrect. CHAP is not used for wireless authentication. PAP is incorrect. PAP offers neither encryption nor authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the security term for disabling unnecessary services on a system and uninstalling unnecessary software?",
    "options": [
      "System reduction",
      "System hardening",
      "Network hardening",
      "Application restriction"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: System hardening is correct. System hardening involves disabling unnecessary services and protocols on a host, as well as uninstalling software that is not needed. Incorrect answers: System reduction is incorrect. System reduction is a nonexistent term in this context and is used as a distractor. Network hardening is incorrect. Network hardening is more about locking down network devices and protocols than hardening a single system. Application restriction is incorrect. Application restriction involves restricting what features exist in an application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following alternate processing sites provides for a moderate ability to recover operations and includes office space and spare networking equipment?",
    "options": [
      "Hot site",
      "Cold site",
      "Time-shared site",
      "Warm site"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Warm site is correct. A warm site offers a middle ground between the different types of alternate processing sites and may contain office space, utilities, and spare equipment needed to facilitate a reasonably quick recovery. Incorrect answers: Cold site is incorrect. A cold site offers recovery within a slow period of time, as you essentially have the facility but no equipment or data at the site. Hot site is incorrect. A hot site has all the equipment required to run the business and also has a form of replication used to replicate data from the original data center to the hot site so that it is ready when disaster strikes. Time-shared site is incorrect. Time-shared sites can be hot, warm, or cold and are characterized by the need to share facilities with another organization."
  },
  {
    "question": "Jason, a network technician for a financial planning company, needs to transfer sensitive files across the network and potentially across the Internet to servers in the head office. Which of the following protocols should he use? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "RDP",
      "FTP",
      "SFTP",
      "FTPS",
      "SNMPv3"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2,
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SFTP and FTPS are correct. Both Secure FTP (SFTP) and FTP Secure (FTPS) can be used to transfer files securely. SFTP is an extension of Secure Shell (SSH) that allows secure transfer and management of files through an SSH channel, whereas FTPS encrypts FTP communication using either the SSL or TLS security protocol. Incorrect answers: RDP is incorrect. RDP is used to remotely access a machine. SNMPv3 is incorrect. SNMPv3 is a management protocol used to monitor and manage devices that support it. FTP is incorrect. FTP is the File Transfer Protocol and does not implement any security or encryption."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the most volatile source of evidence and should be collected first during a computer forensics investigation?",
    "options": [
      "Hard disks",
      "DVDs",
      "Swap file",
      "RAM"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: RAM is correct. RAM is the most volatile source of information and is easily lost. It must be collected first during a computer forensics investigation. Incorrect answer: Hard disks is incorrect. The order of volatility, and order of evidence collection, is cache memory, RAM, swap file/page file, hard disk, logs on remote systems (network), and optical discs such as DVDs. DVDs is incorrect. The order of volatility, and order of evidence collection, is cache memory, RAM, swap file/page file, hard disk, logs on remote systems (network), and optical discs such as DVDs. Swap file is incorrect. The order of volatility, and order of evidence collection, is cache memory, RAM, swap file/page file, hard disk, logs on remote systems (network), and optical discs such as DVDs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the protocol used to encrypt e-mail messages on the network?",
    "options": [
      "HTTPS",
      "S/MIME",
      "IPSec",
      "IPSec"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: S/MIME is correct. Secure/Multimedia Internet Mail Extensions (S/MIME) is used to encrypt e-mail. Incorrect answers: HTTPS is incorrect. HTTPS is used to encrypt web traffic. IPSec is incorrect. IPSec is used to encrypt all IP traffic and can be used to encrypt VPN traffic. IPSec is incorrect. SSH is a secure replacement for Telnet and should be used for remote access to your network devices such as routers and switches."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the LAST step of the penetration test methodology?",
    "options": [
      "Gain access",
      "Profile",
      "Scan and enumerate",
      "Cover tracks"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cover tracks is correct. The last step in actually performing a penetration test is to cover your tracks. This is done to avoid detection, as well as to maintain any access you have obtained in the system. Incorrect answers: Profile is incorrect. Profiling occurs early in the penetration test and is the stage used to research and discover information about your target. Gain access is incorrect. After scanning the systems and identifying services running, you can then exploit those services to gain access to the target systems. Scan and enumerate is incorrect. Scanning and enumeration is the phase used to scan a set of target IP addresses and collect information about the systems, such as the ports that are open and services running on each system."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are types of penetration testing except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Known environment",
      "A little known environment",
      "Unknown environment",
      "Partially known environment"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: A little known environment is correct. A little known environment testing is not a type of penetration testing. Incorrect answers: Unknown environment is incorrect. An unknown environment test, formerly referred to as black box testing, involves a penetration test where the test team has no knowledge of the network being tested. Known environment is incorrect. In a known environment test, formerly known as a white box test, the test team has full and detailed knowledge of the network being tested, including its design, functions, and applications. Partially known environmentis incorrect. In a partially known test, formerly known as gray box testing, the testers may have some knowledge given to them, such as an infrastructure diagram or IP address list."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms is used to describe malicious code written in the application language that helps to automate tasks within the software application?",
    "options": [
      "Boot sector virus",
      "Macro virus",
      "Trojan virus",
      "Executable virus"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Macro virus is correct. A macro virus is really just a script written in an application's macro language. Typically macros are useful in automating tasks by recording and executing those tasks or other actions. A macro virus can be made to execute malicious tasks such as deleting data. Incorrect answers: Trojan virus is incorrect. A Trojan virus is a program you install that opens a back door without your knowledge. Executable virus is incorrect. An executable virus is not written in an application language of a piece of software. It is a compiled program that is executed on its own. Boot sector virus is incorrect. A boot sector virus attacks the boot sector of the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "A rogue access point that is set up to look like an organization's legitimate access point is known as what?",
    "options": [
      "An evil twin",
      "A supplicant",
      "A spoofed AP",
      "FakeAP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: An evil twin is correct. Evil twin is the correct term used to refer to a seemingly identical, legitimate access point that an attacker has set up to cause unsuspecting users to attempt a wireless connection. Incorrect answers: A supplicant is incorrect. Supplicant is a term used in 802.1X wireless authentication to mean a wireless client. A spoofed AP is incorrect. Although an evil twin is essentially a rogue, or spoofed AP, “spoofed AP” is not the term that is used. FakeAP is incorrect. FakeAP is a Linux-based program that broadcasts false SSIDs to effect a denial of service attack on wireless networks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of virus attacks the first sector on the disk that contains operating system loader code and overwrites that code?",
    "options": [
      "Boot sector",
      "Worm",
      "Executable",
      "Macro"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Boot sector is correct. A boot sector virus is a harmful virus that attacks the boot sector code and overwrites it. The boot sector is the first sector on the disk and contains operating system loader code that starts the boot sequence. When a boot sector virus overwrites this sector, it prevents the system from booting from the infected disk. Incorrect answers: Executable is incorrect. An executable virus is attached to an executable file but is not activated until the file is run. Macro is incorrect. A macro virus is written using a macro language that performs a malicious action such as deleting files or e-mailing everyone in your address book. The macro is usually created in a file and then triggered automatically when someone opens the file. Worm is incorrect. A worm virus is able to replicate itself without needing a user to activate the virus and does not typically attack the boot sector of a disk."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered secure alternatives to FTP except which one?",
    "options": [
      "SCP",
      "SFTP",
      "TFTP",
      "FTPS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: TFTP is correct. Trivial File Transfer Protocol (TFTP) is a nonsecure file transfer method that does not encrypt data or provide authentication. It should not be used to replace FTP. Incorrect answers: SFTP is incorrect. SSH File Transfer Protocol (SFTP) is used to perform secure file transfers over a secure shell. FTPS is incorrect. FTP Secure (FTPS), also known as FTP-SSL, is an extension of FTP that creates a secure channel using SSL or TLS. SCP is incorrect. Secure copy (also known as secure copy program, or SCP) is a Linux command for copying files securely."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are troubleshooting a communication problem with an application that sends data to a remote system. What tool can you use to view the traffic being sent on the network by the application?",
    "options": [
      "Protocol analyzer",
      "Frequency analyzer",
      "Switch monitor",
      "Spectrum analyzer"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Protocol analyzer is correct. In order for network traffic to be viewed, it must be sniffed or captured using a protocol analyzer (sometimes called a sniffer). Incorrect answers: Spectrum analyzer is incorrect. A spectrum analyzer cannot be used to capture and view network traffic. Frequency analyzer is incorrect. A frequency analyzer cannot be used to capture and view network traffic. Switch monitor is incorrect. A switch monitor cannot be used to capture and view network traffic."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which security zone is typically located between two security devices and may contain publicly accessible resources such as external web servers?",
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "Intranet",
      "DMZ",
      "Extranet"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DMZ is correct. A demilitarized zone, or DMZ, is a security zone in which publicly accessible servers are usually placed. It is normally (but does not have to be) located between two firewalls. Incorrect answers: Intranet is incorrect. An intranet is typically the private network. Extranet is incorrect. An extranet is a special network zone set aside for business partners who require specific and controlled access to internal resources. VPN is incorrect. A virtual private network (VPN) allows secure remote access by organizational users into the private network."
  },
  {
    "question": "A user has reported a security incident involving the suspicion of malware on their laptop. What phase of the incident response process do you follow next?",
    "options": [
      "Containment",
      "Lessons learned",
      "Identification",
      "Recovery"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Containment is correct. Once a security incident is identified and reported, the first responder's main focus is to contain the incident before it becomes a bigger problem. For example, in the containment phase, the first responder would disconnect an infected system from the network to prevent the malware from spreading. Incorrect answers: Recovery is incorrect. Recovery is the fifth phase of the incident response process and involves the CIRT team recovering the system affected by the security incident. Lessons learned is incorrect. Lessons learned is the last phase of the incident response process, and it involves having the CIRT team look at the security incident and determine if there is a way to prevent it from occurring again. Identification is incorrect. The identification phase is when a user notices a potential security issue and reports the incident."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are types of firewalls except which one?",
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "Stateful",
      "Packet filtering",
      "Application"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: VPN is correct. While many firewalls can perform virtual private network (VPN) functions, VPN is not a type of firewall. Incorrect answers: Packet filtering is incorrect. A packet-filtering firewall is designed to filter traffic based on the layer-3 and layer-4 header of the packet. Stateful is incorrect. A stateful packet-filtering firewall filters traffic based on the layer-3 and layer-4 header, but also by the context of the communication. Application is incorrect. An application layer firewall can filter traffic by the layer-3 and layer-4 header, but also by the payload data within the packet."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which form of malware has the unique characteristic of being able to replicate itself without needing a user to activate it?",
    "options": [
      "Worm",
      "Trojan",
      "Virus",
      "Spyware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Worm is correct. Worms can be activated and spread without user action, such as through network protocols, e-mail, and removable media. Incorrect answers: Virus is incorrect. A regular virus requires the user to open a file to activate it. Trojan is incorrect. A Trojan virus requires the user to run the program that is the Trojan virus. Spyware is incorrect. Spyware requires the user to download or click a link that activates the spyware."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are services offered through cloud computing except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Platform as a Service (PaaS)",
      "Software as a Service (SaaS)",
      "Scalability as a Service (SaaS)",
      "Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Scalability as a Service (SaaS) is correct. Scalability as a Service (SaaS) is not a valid choice of services offered through cloud computing. Incorrect answers: Software as a Service (SaaS) is incorrect. Software as a Service (SaaS) is when an application such as Microsoft 365 or Gmail is provided by the cloud provider. Platform as a Service (PaaS) is incorrect. Platform as a Service (PaaS) provides the computing platform for a solution, such as a development platform or database server. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) is incorrect. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) involves the cloud provider offering virtualization solutions to its customers."
  },
  {
    "question": "The risk that remains after all reducing and mitigation actions have been taken is called what?",
    "options": [
      "Residual risk",
      "Low risk",
      "Mitigated risk",
      "Accepted risk"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Residual risk is correct. Residual risk is what risk remains after all mitigation and reduction strategies have been implemented. Incorrect answers: Low risk is incorrect. Low risk is a level that may be accepted without mitigation or requires little mitigation. Accepted risk is incorrect. Accepted risk is what risk the management authority chooses to accept with or without mitigations in place. Mitigated risk is incorrect. Mitigated risk is the risk that has been reduced to a lower level."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are TCP/IP network security protocols related to HTTPS? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "802.1x",
      "TLS",
      "PKI",
      "SSL"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: TLS and SSL are correct. TLS (Transport Layer Security) and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) can be used to secure HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) communications (HTTPS). TLS supersedes SSL, and both are TCP/IP protocols. Incorrect answers: PKI is incorrect. PKI (Public Key Infrastructure) is not a TCP/IP protocol, but it can secure TCP/IP protocols (such as HTTP). 802.1x is incorrect. 802.1x is an IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers) protocol used to control network access; it's not a TCP/IP protocol."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are part of the risk management team within your company and currently performing a risk assessment of the IT assets. You are responsible for calculating the SLE of a denial of service attack on your company web site. Which of the following formulas would you use?",
    "options": [
      "AV × ARO",
      "AV × EF",
      "ALE × ARO",
      "EF × ARO"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: AV × EF is correct. The single loss expectancy (SLE) of a security event is calculated by the asset value (AV) multiplied by the exposure factor (EF). It should be noted that after you calculate the SLE, you then focus on calculating the annual loss expectancy (ALE), which is the SLE multiplied by the annual rate of occurrence (ARO). Incorrect answers: EF × ARO is incorrect. This does not represent the formula for SLE. ALE × ARO is incorrect. This does not represent the formula for SLE. AV × ARO is incorrect. This does not represent the formula for SLE."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of business continuity plan (BCP) test involves distributing the BCP to the representative for each department to review and to verify that no major components of the BCP have been left out?",
    "options": [
      "Simulation test",
      "Checklist review",
      "Parallel test",
      "Structured walkthrough"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Checklist review is correct. A checklist review is one type of test where the BCP is distributed to the representative for each department to individually review and to verify that no major components of the BCP have been left out. Incorrect answers: Structured walkthrough is incorrect. A structured walkthrough requires the BCP committee to get together and review the BCP as a group. Simulation test is incorrect. A simulation test involves simulating small parts of the plan to see how the flow of the plan works. Parallel test is incorrect. A parallel test involves ensuring that systems can function at the alternate site and that the alternate site is actually functional."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are typically spoofed in attacks except which one?",
    "options": [
      "E-mail",
      "IP addresses",
      "MAC addresses",
      "Encryption keys"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Encryption keys is correct. Encryption keys would be almost impossible to spoof, since an incorrect key simply wouldn't work. Having the correct key would not be spoofing. Incorrect answers: E-mail is incorrect. Identities such as an e-mail addresses are common to spoof in a social engineering attack. IP addresses is incorrect. IP addresses are spoofed in order to bypass access control lists. MAC addresses is incorrect. MAC addresses are spoofed in order to bypass MAC filtering features on a wireless access point."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms describes a trust between two different CAs where each CA trusts the certificates that have been generated by the other CA?",
    "options": [
      "Subordinate",
      "Hierarchical",
      "Cross-certificate",
      "Mesh"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cross-certificate is correct. A cross-certificate trust model is a reciprocal trust, where each of two different root CAs trusts the certificates that have been generated by the other root CA. Incorrect answers: Hierarchical is incorrect. In a mesh model, not only are the other root CAs trusted but also their subordinates, or intermediate CAs. Subordinate is incorrect. A hierarchical model has a root and subordinate CAs. Mesh is incorrect. A subordinate is a lower-level CA in a hierarchical model."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are valid reasons to conduct security and awareness training except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Increase security",
      "Increase risks",
      "Reduce liability",
      "Reduce incidents"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Increase risks is correct. Risk should not be increased by conducting training; instead, it should be decreased. Incorrect answers: Increase security is incorrect. Security and awareness training will increase the overall security of the organization. Reduce incidents is incorrect. Security and awareness training will reduce the chances of a security incident occurring. Reduce liability is incorrect. Security and awareness training will decrease an organization's liability, as they have shown responsibility by providing training to increase security."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding characteristics of vulnerability assessments and penetration testing is true?",
    "options": [
      "Penetration tests are considered passive assessments.",
      "A penetration test identifies areas in the system configuration that make it vulnerable to an attack or security incident.",
      "A vulnerability assessment uses common attack methods to bypass system security.",
      "Vulnerability tests are considered passive assessments."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Vulnerability tests are considered passive assessments is correct. Vulnerability assessments are passive assessments, where only weaknesses in the system configuration that make it vulnerable to an attack or security incident are identified. There is no attempt to actively exploit these weaknesses. Incorrect answers: A penetration test identifies areas in the system configuration that make it vulnerable to an attack or security incident is incorrect. A penetration test is an active assessment and uses common attack methods to bypass system security. A vulnerability assessment uses common attack methods to bypass system security is incorrect. Vulnerability assessments only determine potential weaknesses; they do not actually bypass any security mechanisms. Penetration tests are considered passive assessments is incorrect. Penetration tests are active, not passive, assessments."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following daemons is used in Linux to assist in auditing security events?",
    "options": [
      "crond",
      "named",
      "syslogd",
      "inetd"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: syslogd is correct. The syslog daemon (syslogd) works with the auditing daemon (auditd) to provide system and security event logging in Linux and Unix systems. Incorrect answers: inetd is incorrect. The inetd daemon is used to control access to network services. named is incorrect. The named daemon is used to manage the DNS service. crond is incorrect. The crond daemon manages scheduled tasks."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a mandatory access control (MAC) model, who is responsible for determining the data classification on the data?",
    "options": [
      "User",
      "IT manager",
      "Data custodian",
      "Data owner"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Data owner is correct. The data owner understands the value of the data and decides on the sensitivity of the information, such as secret or top secret, when dealing with classification systems. Incorrect answers: IT manager is incorrect. The IT manager is responsible for planning and leading computer-related tasks within the company, but is not responsible for assigning classifications to data. User is incorrect. Users may use the data, but they do not assign classifications to data. Data custodian is incorrect. The data custodian is the IT staff. They are not responsible for assigning a classification level to the data, but may be responsible for implementing protective controls on the data based on the classification level assigned."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are valid risk management strategies except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Risk elimination",
      "Risk mitigation",
      "Risk acceptance",
      "Risk transference"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Risk elimination is correct. Risk can never be completely eliminated, only dealt with. Incorrect answers: Risk mitigation is incorrect. Mitigation is a risk management strategy. Risk acceptance is incorrect. Acceptance is a risk management strategy. Risk transference is incorrect. Transference is a risk management strategy."
  },
  {
    "question": "After seeing a few news stories about employees taking copies of sensitive data from their companies, your manager decides to prevent the use of USB drives. What security feature would you suggest?",
    "options": [
      "NAC",
      "TPM",
      "CRL",
      "DLP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DLP is correct. Data loss prevention (DLP) is a set of technologies that can be used to prevent data leakage outside your organization. Incorrect answers: NAC is incorrect. Network access control (NAC) is used to enforce that clients are of good health before they can connect to the network. CRL is incorrect. A certificate revocation list (CRL) is a list of certificates that have been revoked. TPM is incorrect. A Trusted Platform Module (TPM) is a chip that contains encryption keys."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ashlyn is a security officer within your organization and wants to set up a device that is able to monitor and block suspicious traffic on the network. What type of device does she want to use?",
    "options": [
      "In-band IPS",
      "Out-of-band IDS",
      "Host-based IPS",
      "Network-based IDS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: In-band IPS is correct. An in-band IPS is an intrusion protection system that is placed inline, which means that the traffic must pass through it to make it to the destination systems. This allows the IPS to not only monitor traffic but block the traffic if it is suspicious. Incorrect answers: Network-based IDS is incorrect. A network-based IDS (NIDS) does not take corrective action. Out-of-band IDS is incorrect. An out-of-band IDS is a device that simply monitors traffic that travels through the network by having a copy of the traffic sent to it; this type of IDS sends out alerts but does not take corrective action. Host-based IPS is incorrect. A host-based IPS (HIPS) only monitors activity and takes corrective action on the one system running it."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of intrusion detection system identifies suspicious activity by monitoring log files on the system?",
    "options": [
      "NIPS",
      "ACL",
      "HIDS",
      "NIDS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: HIDS is correct. A host-based intrusion detection system (HIDS) monitors local system activity and logs for indications of an attack. Incorrect answers: NIDS is incorrect. An NIDS is a network-based intrusion detection system and does not monitor host log files. NIPS is incorrect. An NIPS is a network-based intrusion prevention system and works on the network instead of the host. ACL is incorrect. An ACL is an access control list and is used to allow or deny traffic through a router or grant/deny permissions to resources."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a card that is added to a system and contains a crypto-processor to perform asymmetric cryptographic functions at the hardware level?",
    "options": [
      "HSM",
      "TPM",
      "EFS",
      "PGP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: HSM is correct. A hardware security module (HSM) is a card that is added to a system and contains a crypto-processor to perform asymmetric cryptographic functions at the hardware level and can also contain chips that store the crypto-keys to be used by the system. Incorrect answers: TPM is incorrect. A Trusted Platform Module (TPM) can perform the same functions as an HSM, but it's not an add-in card. It is usually a chip that comes already installed on the motherboard of a computer or device. EFS is incorrect. Encrypting File System (EFS) is a Windows NTFS feature that encrypts files. PGP is incorrect. Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) is a software-based encryption program."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are items that should be configured in a system baseline except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Memory usage",
      "Protocol usage",
      "Installed services",
      "Permissions"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Memory usage is correct. Memory is a dynamic resource and usually can't be configured in terms of how it is used in any given moment. Incorrect answers: Protocol usage is incorrect. You can control what protocols a system will use in the configuration baseline. Installed services is incorrect. You can control what services are running on a system within the configuration baseline. Permissions is incorrect. You can configure default permissions within the configuration baseline."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are steps in creating and maintaining a business continuity plan (BCP) except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact assessment",
      "Develop policies",
      "Project initiation",
      "Test the plan"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Develop policies is correct. Developing policies is not a phase in creating a BCP. The major steps in creating a BCP are (1) project initiation, (2) business impact assessment, (3) develop the plan, (4) test the plan, and (5) maintain the plan. Incorrect answer: Project initiation is incorrect. Project initiation is the first step in creating a BCP. Business impact assessment is incorrect. The second step in creating a BCP is to perform a business impact assessment (BIA). Test the plan is incorrect. The fourth step in creating a BCP is to test the plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager has asked you to perform a security assessment of the servers to determine what vulnerabilities may exist with each of the systems. She has requested that you not attack the systems but instead just determine what vulnerabilities exist. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "Metasploit",
      "Nessus",
      "NetFlow",
      "Wireshark"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Nessus is correct. Nessus is a vulnerability scanner that is used to identify vulnerabilities on a system. Incorrect answers: Wireshark is incorrect. Wireshark is a packet capturing and analysis tool. Metasploit is incorrect. Metasploit is an exploitation framework that comes with a number of different exploits to attack different types of systems. NetFlow is incorrect. NetFlow is a feature of Cisco routers that allows you to collect and display the packets that enter or leave an interface."
  },
  {
    "question": "A term that describes a weakness in the configuration of hardware or software is known as what?",
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability",
      "Risk",
      "Threat",
      "Exposure"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Vulnerability is correct. These are all key elements of risk, but an asset's weakness is a vulnerability. Incorrect answers: Risk is incorrect. Risk is the likelihood that a threat will significantly impact a vulnerability. Exposure is incorrect. Exposure is the percentage of the asset's value you expect to lose if the threat occurs. Threat is incorrect. A threat is an event or entity that can cause harm to an asset."
  },
  {
    "question": "Alison, the senior security officer within your organization, has requested that you create a plan for a passive security test that identifies configuration mistakes with an asset. What type of test would you plan?",
    "options": [
      "Penetration test",
      "Code review",
      "Vulnerability scan",
      "Risk assessment"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Vulnerability scan is correct. A vulnerability scan is considered a passive test because it only involves reviewing the configuration of a system to determine if there are any vulnerabilities. Incorrect answers: Penetration test is incorrect. A penetration test is considered an active test because you are actually interacting with the target system and trying to bypass the security controls. Risk assessment is incorrect. A risk assessment helps identify risks for each asset. Code review is incorrect. A code review involves reviewing the code of an application to look for flaws."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which key recovery concept requires a minimum number of personnel to facilitate a key recovery?",
    "options": [
      "Escrow",
      "Recovery agent",
      "Separation of duties",
      "M of N control"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: M of N control is correct. The concept of M of N control requires a minimum number of personnel to participate in a key recovery. For example, you may require two out of three authorized persons to perform key recovery. Incorrect answers: Separation of duties is incorrect. Separation of duties applies to all privileged functions, not to key control. Recovery agent is incorrect. A recovery agent, typically used in Windows EFS implementations, is used to recover a key if an individual leaves an organization. Escrow is incorrect. Typically, only one person is required for key recovery using escrow. Escrow is a term used to describe a third party holding the keys for the organization."
  },
  {
    "question": "A security audit of your company reveals that all corporate computers are reachable internally across the LAN, meaning they receive and process all packets that are sent to them. Your help-desk personnel must have RDP and SSH access to all hosts. You would like to harden your internal computers. What should you do, assuming default ports are being used? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Install a host-based virus scanner on the computers.",
      "Allow inbound TCP port 22 and 3389 packets.",
      "Install a host-based firewall on the computers.",
      "Allow inbound TCP port 25 and 389 packets."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Allow inbound TCP port 22 and 3389 packets and Install a host-based firewall on the computers are correct. A host-based firewall can be used to block inbound traffic other than exceptions, such as TCP port 22 (SSH) and port 3389 (RDP). Firewalls that block by port numbers are called layer 4 firewalls. Layer 7 firewalls can examine all packet data including content related to specific applications. Incorrect answers: Allow inbound TCP port 25 and 389 packets is incorrect. These port numbers (25 for SMTP and 389 for LDAP) do not match SSH and RDP. Install a host-based virus scanner on the computers is incorrect. The question focuses on host reachability over the network. Virus scanners are not related to this type of security hardening."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following technologies typically use rule-based management?",
    "options": [
      "Databases",
      "Routers, firewalls, and proxy servers",
      "Operating systems",
      "Web servers"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Routers, firewalls, and proxy servers is correct. Network and security devices such as routers, firewalls, and proxy servers use rules and rulesets to determine access to resources. Incorrect answers: Operating systems is incorrect. Operating systems typically do not use rule-based management. Databases is incorrect. Databases typically do not use rule-based management. Web servers is incorrect. Web servers typically do not use rule-based management."
  },
  {
    "question": "A disaster recovery plan should include all of the following items except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Passwords",
      "Steps for rebuilding servers",
      "Location of software and CD keys",
      "Location of backup media"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Passwords is correct. Passwords should not be included in the actual plan. The location of stored passwords for root accounts may be included, if necessary, but typically users with privileges to perform a certain action should be listed, and not any user accounts' passwords. Incorrect answers: Location of software and CD keys is incorrect. The location of software and CD keys should be contained within the disaster recovery plan so that software can be installed on new systems during recovery. Location of backup media is incorrect. The location of backup media should be contained within the disaster recovery plan so that the media can be retrieved in a timely manner. Steps for rebuilding servers is incorrect. The disaster recovery plan should contain the steps to rebuild servers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following refers to an exploit in an application that is unknown to the developers of the application?",
    "options": [
      "LDAP injection",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "XML injection",
      "Zero day"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Zero day is correct. A zero-day exploit is one that may be discovered by hackers before the vendor even knows it is there and can develop mitigations or a patch for it. Incorrect answers: XML injection is incorrect. XML injection is an application attack involving the attacker inputting XML code into an unsuspecting application. LDAP injection is incorrect. LDAP injection is an application attack involving the attacker inputting LDAP code into an unsuspecting application. Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting attempts to inject client-side code into a server so it will be sent to, and executed on, other clients."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms is most accurately defined by the amount of time a business can survive without a particular function?",
    "options": [
      "Maximum tolerable downtime (MTD)",
      "Mean time between failures (MTBF)",
      "Recovery time objective (RTO)",
      "Recovery point objective (RPO)"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Maximum tolerable downtime (MTD) is correct. The maximum tolerable downtime (MTD) indicates how long an asset may be down or offline without seriously impacting the organization. Incorrect answers: Mean time between failures (MTBF) is incorrect. The mean time between failures is an estimate of how long a piece of equipment will perform before failure. Recovery point objective (RPO) is incorrect. The recovery point objective (RPO) is how much data may be lost during a failure or disaster. Recovery time objective (RTO) is incorrect. The recovery time objective (RTO) refers to the maximum amount of time it must take to recover the system or data after a disaster occurs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Susan has received an e-mail message from her brother stating that if she forwards the e-mail to 10 different people, she will receive good fortune over the next three years. Susan forwards the e-mail. What policy has Susan violated in this example?",
    "options": [
      "Acceptable usage policy",
      "Least privilege policy",
      "Need-to-know policy",
      "Social engineering policy"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Acceptable usage policy is correct. An acceptable use policy (AUP) defines what users may and may not do with regard to information systems, including e-mail. Incorrect answers: Social engineering policy is incorrect. A social engineering policy would apply to security auditors and inform them of the types of social engineering activity that can be performed during an assessment. Least privilege policy is incorrect. The principle of least privilege means only grant users the level of access they need to perform their job. Need-to-know policy is incorrect. Need-to-know means that staff are only given access to information that is relevant to them and their job."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following technologies would allow you to create communication boundaries by dividing your network into different broadcast domains without using multiple routers?",
    "options": [
      "Firewalls",
      "VLANs",
      "Security zones",
      "Mutual authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: VLANs is correct. Virtual LANs (VLANs) are used to segment hosts into logical networks and to create secure communication boundaries between them. VLANs are implemented on switches. Incorrect answers: Security zones is incorrect. Security zones such as extranets and DMZs are used to segregate networks to protect private networks from public ones such as the Internet. Mutual authentication is incorrect. Mutual authentication requires that two hosts such as a client and server both confirm each other's identity. Firewalls is incorrect. Firewalls are used to filter types of network traffic but are typically not used to segregate networks into different broadcast domains."
  },
  {
    "question": "Over the weekend you configure IPSec on your internal client workstations. Some internal servers are configured with IPSec, but not all of them. On Monday morning the help desk is flooded with trouble tickets stating that users can connect to some internal servers but not others. Which of the following is the most likely cause of the connectivity problems?",
    "options": [
      "Workstation must be joined to Active Directory to use IPSec.",
      "IPSec can be used only with VPNs.",
      "Workstations are configured to require IPSec connectivity.",
      "Workstations have IPv6 enabled."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Workstations are configured to require IPSec connectivity is correct. What most likely happened is the client workstation IPSec configurations are set to require IPSec connectivity. This means they can communicate only with hosts configured with the appropriate IPSec settings (which in the question equates to some, but not all, internal servers). Incorrect answers: IPSec can be used only with VPNs is incorrect. IPSec does not have to be used with a VPN tunnel. Workstation must be joined to Active Directory to use IPSec is incorrect. Microsoft Active Directory (AD) is not required to use IPSec. Workstations have IPv6 enabled is incorrect. IPv6 does not have an impact on the functionality of IPSec."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following algorithms produces a 160-bit hash?",
    "options": [
      "RSA",
      "SHA-1",
      "AES",
      "MD5"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SHA-1 is correct. SHA-1 (Secure Hashing Algorithm 1) produces a 160-bit hash. Incorrect answers: MD5 is incorrect. MD5 (Message Digest version 5) produces a 128-bit hash. AES is incorrect. AES is not a hashing algorithm but rather is a symmetric encryption algorithm. RSA is incorrect. RSA is not a hashing algorithm but rather is an asymmetric encryption algorithm."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to a form of phishing in which the goal is to send an e-mail to trick someone very important in the organization into giving out their account name and password",
    "options": [
      "Gold phishing",
      "Vishing",
      "Whaling",
      "Impersonation"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Whaling is correct. Whaling refers to targeting a specific individual, usually someone important in the organization, with the intent to get personal information from them. Incorrect answers: Vishing is incorrect. Vishing refers to phishing using telephone or Voice over IP (VoIP) technology. Impersonation is incorrect. Impersonation is a different type of social engineering attack where an individual is spoofed or impersonated. Gold phishing is incorrect. Gold phishing is not a valid term."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of social engineering attack involves the attacker pretending to be an administrator, executive, or other key member of the organization?",
    "options": [
      "Whaling",
      "Pretext attack",
      "Impersonation",
      "Tailgating"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Impersonation is correct. Impersonation is pretending to be someone else, usually someone important, to execute a social engineering attack. Incorrect answers: Pretext attack is incorrect. A pretext is simply an elaborate story, with believable detail and props added, that may be used to carry out any social engineering attack. Tailgating is incorrect. Tailgating involves entering a restricted area by closely following behind someone after they have authenticated by using a badge or card. Whaling is incorrect. Whaling is a form of phishing attack, involving e-mail, where an important person is targeted but not impersonated."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are reviewing the contents of logs on a web server that has been involved in a security incident. What command would you use to search the log for a specific pattern of characters?",
    "options": [
      "head",
      "chmod",
      "tail",
      "grep"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: grep is correct. grep is a command-line tool in Linux that allows you to search for lines of text that match the pattern of characters specified using a regular expression. Incorrect answers: head is incorrect. head is a Linux command used to report back the beginning content of a file (by default, the first 10 lines). tail is incorrect. tail is a Linux command used to print out the last 10 lines of a file, by default. chmod is incorrect. chmod is a Linux command used to modify the permissions on a file."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager would like to implement a cloud service that provides e-mail access in the web browser and allows users to read e-mail from anywhere on the Internet. What type of cloud solution is this?",
    "options": [
      "Infrastructure as a Service",
      "Platform as a Service",
      "Security as a Service",
      "Software as a Service"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Software as a Service is correct. Software as a Service (SaaS) is when an application, such as Microsoft 365 or Gmail, is provided by the cloud provider. Incorrect answers: Platform as a Service is incorrect. Platform as a Service (PaaS) provides the computing platform for a solution, such as a development platform or database server. Infrastructure as a Service is incorrect. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) involves the cloud provider offering virtualization solutions to its customers. Security as a Service is incorrect. Security as a Service falls into the Anything as a Service (XaaS) category and is a cloud solution that involves the cloud provider offering security solutions such as anti-malware, anti-spam, intrusion detection services, and penetration testing services."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements does not accurately describe the characteristics of block and stream ciphers?",
    "options": [
      "A block cipher means the information is broken into fixed-length blocks (typically 64-bit chunks), and then each block is encrypted.",
      "In a block cipher, the plain-text bits are typically encrypted with the bits of a key by using an exclusive OR (XOR) function.",
      "A stream cipher encrypts the entire stream of text instead of breaking the data into blocks.",
      "In a stream cipher, the plain-text bits are typically encrypted with the bits of a key by using an exclusive OR (XOR) function."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: In a block cipher, the plain-text bits are typically encrypted with the bits of a key by using an exclusive OR (XOR) function is correct. Stream ciphers use the XOR function, which is performed continuously on the plain text rather than applied one block at a time. Incorrect answers: A block cipher means the information is broken into fixed-length blocks (typically 64-bit chunks), and then each block is encrypted is incorrect. With a block cipher, the information is broken into fixed-length blocks and then the block is encrypted. A stream cipher encrypts the entire stream of text instead of breaking the data into blocks is incorrect. A stream cipher encrypts the entire stream of data. In a stream cipher, the plain-text bits are typically encrypted with the bits of a key by using an exclusive OR (XOR) function is incorrect. Stream ciphers typically use an XOR function with the bits of a key to perform the encryption."
  },
  {
    "question": "A digital certificate may contain all of the following pieces of information except what?",
    "options": [
      "Algorithm",
      "Private key of the issuer",
      "Serial number",
      "Public key of the subject"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Private key of the issuer is correct. The issuer's private key is used to digitally sign the certificate, thus ensuring authenticity, but it's not included in the certificate itself, as this would compromise the key. Incorrect answers: Public key of the subject is incorrect. A digital certificate may contain the public key of the subject or owner of the certificate. Serial number is incorrect. A digital certificate is assigned a serial number. Algorithm is incorrect. A digital certificate does contain information on the algorithms used by the certificate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a risk mitigation strategy that involves transferring risk to another entity?",
    "options": [
      "Cybersecurity insurance",
      "Alternate site",
      "Service level agreement",
      "Separation of duties"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cybersecurity insurance is correct. Insurance is a method of risk transference where the organization pays a premium for the insurance company to assume the risk. If a disaster or event occurs, the organization is paid for its losses. Incorrect answers: Separation of duties is incorrect. Separation of duties transfers key duties to another individual but does not transfer the risk away from the organization. Alternate site is incorrect. An alternate site is used to transfer operations from a primary site in the event of a disaster, but the risk is still borne by the organization. Service level agreement is incorrect. A service level agreement between two parties specifies levels of service and support, but the organization still maintains risk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following simple command-line tools would be used from the host to determine what open ports a host is listening on?",
    "options": [
      "nbtstat",
      "netstat",
      "ping",
      "ifconfig"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: netstat is correct. netstat is a tool found on both Unix/Linux and Windows hosts that can give network statistics and connection information, including port usage. This would help determine if a host is listening on an unexpected or unwanted port. Incorrect answers: nbtstat is incorrect. nbtstat is a command found only on Windows hosts and gives NetBIOS usage information. ping is incorrect. ping is found on both Unix/Linux and Windows hosts but only sends simple ICMP requests to a host. ifconfig is incorrect. ifconfig is found only on Unix and Linux hosts and only gives network interface configuration information."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have recovered a system after it was hit with a virus. What is the phase you perform next, which is the last phase of the incident response process?",
    "options": [
      "Eradication",
      "Containment",
      "Preparation",
      "Lessons learned"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Lessons learned is correct. The lessons learned phase is the last phase of the incident response process and involves identifying how to prevent similar incidents in the future. Incorrect answers: Eradication is incorrect. The eradication phase is the fourth phase of the incident response process and involves removing the issue that caused the security incident. Containment is incorrect. The containment phase is performed right after the incident is identified and is designed to prevent the incident from becoming a bigger problem. Preparation is incorrect. Preparation is the first phase of the incident response process and involves assembling a Computer Incident Response Team (CIRT) and creating incident response procedures."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered to be effective mobile device security controls except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Screen locks",
      "Use of WEP",
      "Remote wipe/sanitization",
      "Device encryption"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Use of WEP is correct. Even on mobile devices such as smart phones and tablets, WEP should not be used to connect to wireless networks due to its inherent weaknesses. Incorrect answers: Screen locks is incorrect. You should use a screen lock on your mobile device that automatically activates after a short period of idle time. Device encryption is incorrect. You should use device encryption to encrypt the contents on the mobile device. Remote wipe/sanitization is incorrect. If the device is lost or stolen, you should use remote wipe/sanitization features to ensure the data is erased off the device."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are experiencing network performance issues with your web server. What tool would you use to capture network traffic in order to troubleshoot the issue?",
    "options": [
      "tcpdump",
      "Nessus",
      "nmap",
      "traceroute"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: tcpdump is correct. tcpdump is a common Linux tool used to capture traffic and store the packets in a file. Incorrect answer: Nessus is incorrect. Nessus is a vulnerability scanner. nmap is incorrect. nmap is a port scanner with capabilities to perform ping sweeps and service identification. traceroute is incorrect. traceroute is a command used to display the pathway that a packet takes to reach the destination."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is typically conducted as a first step in the overall business continuity/disaster recovery strategy?",
    "options": [
      "Business continuity plan",
      "System backup plan",
      "Disaster recovery plan",
      "Business impact analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Business impact analysis is correct. The business impact analysis (BIA) is a critical first step in developing the business continuity plan (BCP). It involves determining what risks are present and their effects on the business and its assets. Incorrect answers: Business continuity plan is incorrect. The BCP is the overall and final product that the BIA contributes to. The BIA must be completed as one of the first steps, as it essentially is the risk assessment for the BCP. Disaster recovery plan is incorrect. The disaster recovery plan (DRP) concerns itself with recovering the assets and operations of the business immediately following a disaster. System backup plan is incorrect. A system backup plan is but one element of the DRP and may or may not be one of the first things accomplished for that plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager would like you to ensure that employees are not able to access the accounting systems. What action would you take?",
    "options": [
      "Disable ports for the accounting systems.",
      "Configure a WAP.",
      "Place the accounting systems in their own VLAN.",
      "Set the WPA2 key to a new value."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Place the accounting systems in their own VLAN is correct. To control communication, you can place the accounting systems in a different VLAN from the rest of the network. Incorrect answers: Configure a WAP is incorrect. You would not configure a WAP because you are not trying to provide wireless access. Disable ports for the accounting systems is incorrect. You cannot disable the ports the accounting systems are connected to because that will prevent everyone from being able to communicate with them. Set the WPA2 key to a new value is incorrect. Changing the WPA2 key will not help because this is not a wireless scenario."
  },
  {
    "question": "There is a new vulnerability discovered for systems running Remote Desktop. What tool could you use to discover which systems on the network are running Remote Desktop?",
    "options": [
      "dd",
      "ping",
      "traceroute",
      "nmap"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: nmap is correct. nmap is used to identify ports open and services running on a system. Incorrect answers: ping is incorrect. ping is used to verify communication with a target system. traceroute is incorrect. traceroute is used to see the path that packets are taking to reach a destination system. dd is incorrect. dd is a tool used to create a forensics image of a hard drive or memory."
  },
  {
    "question": "An attack that injects data into a web form that makes calls to a directory database is called what?",
    "options": [
      "XML injection",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "LDAP injection",
      "SQL injection"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: LDAP injection is correct. LDAP injection is an attack that can send malicious data to a web form that in turn makes calls or queries to a directory database, such as an X.500-compliant database like Active Directory, or to any other LDAP database. Incorrect answers: Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting attempts to inject client-side code into a server so it will be sent to, and executed on, other clients. XML injection is incorrect. XML injection is used to input XML code into an application to manipulate how the application works. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection attacks are used to input database commands into an application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeff is a user on the network and needs to be able to change the system time. Instead of adding Jeff to the Administrators group, you give Jeff the “Change the system time” right. What security principle are you following in this example?",
    "options": [
      "Separation of duties",
      "Role-based access control",
      "Least privilege",
      "Discretionary access control"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Least privilege is correct. The principle of least privilege allows users to have only the privileges necessary to perform their duties and no more. Incorrect answers: Separation of duties is incorrect. Separation of duties requires critical roles to be split among personnel so no one user has the privileges to commit fraud or to abuse their role. Role-based access control is incorrect. Role-based access control is an access control model that involves granting access based on the roles a user is a member of. Discretionary access control is incorrect. Discretionary access control is an access control model that involves granting users access by placing them in a permission list (an access control list)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is used to identify certificates that are no longer valid for use?",
    "options": [
      "CAL",
      "CA",
      "PKS",
      "CRL"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: CRL is correct. The certificate revocation list (CRL) is used to identify invalid certificates. Incorrect answers: CAL is incorrect. A CAL is a client access license. PKS is incorrect. PKS is a cryptographic file standard. CA is incorrect. A CA is a certificate authority, which issues certificates."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a function provided by cryptography?",
    "options": [
      "Encryption",
      "Availability",
      "Hashing",
      "Authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Availability is correct. Cryptography does not provide for availability. Incorrect answer: Encryption is incorrect. Cryptography provides for encryption, hashing, and authentication, and primarily focuses on the confidentiality and integrity facets of the CIA model. Hashing is incorrect. Cryptography provides for encryption, hashing, and authentication, and primarily focuses on the confidentiality and integrity facets of the CIA model. Authentication is incorrect. Cryptography provides for encryption, hashing, and authentication, and primarily focuses on the confidentiality and integrity facets of the CIA model."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves the attacker placing themselves in the middle of the communication path between the intended victims?",
    "options": [
      "DNS poisoning",
      "On-path attack",
      "MAC flooding",
      "Zero-day attack"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: On-path attack is correct. An on-path attack was formerly known as a man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack, where the attacker injects themselves in the communication pathway of two parties so that they can receive a copy of all the traffic. Incorrect answers: MAC flooding is incorrect. MAC flooding is when the attacker floods the switch with bogus MAC address and port information, causing the switch to start flooding all the frames. This is one technique used to place the attacker “on path.” DNS poisoning is incorrect. DNS poisoning is when the attacker modifies the DNS records to lead the victim to the attacker's system when they communicate with a fully qualified domain name (FQDN) such as www.mybank.com. Zero-day attack is incorrect. A zero-day attack or zero-day exploit is an attack on a vulnerability not known to the vendor of the product being exploited."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company uses a number of different types of mobile devices such as laptops, smart phones, and tablets. Your manager is concerned about a malicious app being installed on the devices and the devices being stolen. What solution would you recommend to better manage and monitor the mobile devices?",
    "options": [
      "CASB",
      "DLP",
      "MDM",
      "802.1X"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: MDM is correct. Mobile device management (MDM) software is enterprise software used to manage all your mobile devices from a central location. You can deploy policies to the devices that control the features and applications on them. Incorrect answers: DLP is incorrect. Data loss prevention (DLP) is a technology used to help prevent data leaks or data exfiltration. CASB is incorrect. A cloud access security broker (CASB) is a security service that sits between your on-premises environment and your cloud provider's environment. The CASB allows you to define security policies that apply to network traffic flowing outside your current on-premises environment to the cloud. 802.1X is incorrect. 802.1X is a method for implementing RADIUS authentication when someone connects to the wired or wireless network."
  },
  {
    "question": "A printed e-mail would be considered which kind of evidence?w",
    "options": [
      "Real evidence",
      "Documentary evidence",
      "Direct evidence",
      "Demonstrative evidence"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Documentary evidence is correct. Documentary evidence is usually a printed form of evidence, a recording, or a photograph. Incorrect answers: Real evidence is incorrect. Real (or physical) evidence is a tangible object presented in court (for example, a weapon). Direct evidence is incorrect. Direct evidence is testimony from someone who actually witnessed the event. Demonstrative evidence is incorrect. Demonstrative evidence involves presenting a physical object that displays the results of an event that occurred."
  },
  {
    "question": "A policy is which type of security control?",
    "options": [
      "Physical",
      "Logical",
      "Administrative",
      "Operational"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Administrative is correct. Administrative controls (also called managerial controls) include security policies. Incorrect answers: Operational is incorrect. Operational controls cover items such as backups. Physical is incorrect. Physical controls are used to control aspects of the facility, including fences, guards, and mantraps (also known as access control vestibules). Logical is incorrect. Logical controls, also called technical controls, cover security measures such as firewalls, permissions, and so forth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Sara, the IT manager within your organization, wants to place a VPN concentrator on the network to accept VPN traffic from clients on the Internet. Where should she place the VPN concentrator?",
    "options": [
      "DMZ",
      "Private network",
      "Internet",
      "Public network"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DMZ is correct. The VPN concentrator should be placed in the DMZ, with ports on the external firewall allowing VPN traffic to pass through it. Incorrect answers: Private network is incorrect. The VPN concentrator should not be placed on the private network. Public network is incorrect. The VPN concentrator should not be placed on the public network, which is the same as saying “the Internet.” Internet is incorrect. The VPN concentrator should not be placed on the Internet."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the most effective way to prevent social engineering attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Document destruction",
      "Training",
      "Spam filtering",
      "Password complexity"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Training is correct. Training is the most effective means of preventing social engineering attacks. Incorrect answers: Password complexity is incorrect. Password complexity is designed to prevent dictionary attacks against passwords. Spam filtering is incorrect. A spam filter will help block spam messages from reaching your inbox. Document destruction is incorrect. Document destruction is a method to help prevent someone from finding sensitive information when they perform some dumpster diving."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following steps in a Secure Sockets Layer transaction between a client and server occurs LAST?",
    "options": [
      "The encrypted information is sent to the web server, which decrypts and obtains the symmetric key (session key).",
      "The client creates a random symmetric key (known as a session key).",
      "The client validates the certificate and ensures it has not expired or been revoked.",
      "The server sends the public key to the client."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: The encrypted information is sent to the web server, which decrypts and obtains the symmetric key (session key) is correct. The last step involves the client sending the session key, encrypted with the server's public key, to the server. The following are the high-level steps in an SSL transaction: 1. The client sends a request for a web page to the secure web site by using https:// in the URL. This makes a connection to port 443 by default. 2. The server sends the public key to the client. 3. The client validates the certificate and ensures it has not expired or been revoked. 4. The client creates a random symmetric key (known as a session key) used to encrypt the web page content, and then encrypts the symmetric key with the public key obtained from the web server. 5. The encrypted information is sent to the web server. The web server decrypts and obtains the symmetric key (session key). The web server uses the symmetric key to encrypt information between the client and the server. Incorrect qanswers: The server sends the public key to the client is incorrect. The server sending the public key to the client occurs in step 2. The client creates a random symmetric key (known as a session key) is incorrect. The creation of the random symmetric key is done in step 4. The client validates the certificate and ensures it has not expired or been revoked is incorrect. The certificate is validated in step 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following versions of the Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP) is used to encapsulate EAP messages over a secure tunnel that uses TLS?",
    "options": [
      "EAP-PSK",
      "PEAP",
      "LEAP",
      "EAP-MD5"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: PEAP is correct. Protected Extensible Authentication Protocol (PEAP) is used to encapsulate EAP messages over a secure tunnel that uses Transport Layer Security (TLS). Incorrect answers: EAP-MD5 is incorrect. EAP-MD5 does not encapsulate EAP messages over a secure tunnel that uses TLS. LEAP is incorrect. LEAP does not encapsulate EAP messages over a secure tunnel that uses TLS. EAP-PSK is incorrect. EAP-PSK does not encapsulate EAP messages over a secure tunnel that uses TLS."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are monitoring requests into the web server and notice one that contains this URL: http://site/processpayment.asp?txtName=<script>alert('hello');</script> What type of attack is occurring?",
    "options": [
      "XSS",
      "CSRF",
      "SQL injection",
      "SSL"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: XSS is correct. Cross-site scripting (XSS) is a popular form of attack that involves the hacker inserting script code into a form on a web page and submitting the script code to the server. Incorrect answers: CSRF is incorrect. Cross-site request forgery (CSRF) is when the attacker tricks a person into clicking a link that makes a call to another site that the user is already authenticated to. For example, the link may change the user's password on the other site. SSL is incorrect. Secure Socket Layer (SSL) is a protocol used to encrypt communication such as web traffic. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection is when the attacker inputs SQL commands as input in order to manipulate the system and the data in the database."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the security officer for a movie rental company that rents digital videos that can be downloaded by the customer for offline viewing on their mobile device. Your manager would like to implement a security solution that prevents someone from viewing the movie after their two-day rental is up. What would you recommend?",
    "options": [
      "Masking",
      "Data loss prevention",
      "Hashing",
      "Rights management"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Rights management is correct. Rights management services allows you to protect digital assets using cryptography services. With rights management services, you can have content expire so that it can no longer be viewed after a period of time. You can also prevent the printing of documents and the forwarding of e-mail messages. Incorrect answers: Data loss prevention is incorrect. Data loss prevention is designed to prevent data leakage and data exfiltration, where someone makes a copy of sensitive company information. Masking is incorrect. Masking is the hiding of sensitive information on the screen. Hashing is incorrect. Hashing is used to verify the integrity of data."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following accurately describe the differences between TACACS and RADIUS except which one?",
    "options": [
      "TACACS uses TCP.",
      "TACACS encrypts only passwords between the client and server.",
      "RADIUS uses UDP.",
      "RADIUS encrypts only passwords between the client and server."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: TACACS encrypts only passwords between the client and server is correct. TACACS encrypts all information between the client and server, whereas RADIUS only encrypts the passwords. Incorrect answers: TACACS uses TCP is incorrect. TACACS does use TCP. RADIUS uses UDP is incorrect. RADIUS does use UDP. RADIUS encrypts only passwords between the client and server is incorrect. RADIUS only encrypts the passwords between the client and server and not all of their communication."
  },
  {
    "question": "You wish to send an encrypted message to Bob. Which of the following is used to encrypt a message sent to Bob in a PKI environment?",
    "options": [
      "Private key",
      "Hash value",
      "Public key",
      "Symmetric key"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Public key is correct. Bob's public key is used to encrypt a message for him. Bob would then decrypt the message with his private key. Incorrect answers: Symmetric key is incorrect. A symmetric key is not used to encrypt a message within a PKI environment. Private key is incorrect. The private key would be used to decrypt, not encrypt, the message in this scenario. Hash value is incorrect. A hash value is not used to encrypt a message within a PKI environment."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the formula for calculating risk?",
    "options": [
      "Risk = probability × loss",
      "Risk = threat + vulnerability",
      "Risk = SLE × ARO",
      "Risk = impact × loss"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Risk = probability × loss is correct. Risk is the probability times the loss (or impact). Incorrect answers: Risk = impact × loss is incorrect. To calculate risk, you use the formula of risk = probability × loss. Risk = threat + vulnerability is incorrect. To calculate risk, you use the formula of risk = probability × loss. Risk = SLE × ARO is incorrect. To calculate risk, you use the formula of risk = probability × loss."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes a minimum password age setting?",
    "options": [
      "Users must change passwords after a certain amount of time.",
      "Passwords cannot be reused until they have been expired a certain amount of time.",
      "Users must not change passwords until a certain date.",
      "Users must wait a certain amount of time before they are allowed to change passwords."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Users must wait a certain amount of time before they are allowed to change passwords is correct. A minimum password age requires users to wait a certain amount of time before they are allowed to change their password again. Incorrect answers: Users must change passwords after a certain amount of time is incorrect. A maximum password age setting requires users to change their password after a certain amount of time. Users must not change passwords until a certain date is incorrect. Passwords are typically good only for a certain amount of time, not through a certain date. Passwords cannot be reused until they have been expired a certain amount of time is incorrect. Passwords typically cannot be reused until a certain number of password changes have occurred, preventing the use of the last specified number of passwords."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of malware is difficult to detect and replaces key operating system files?",
    "options": [
      "Worm",
      "Rootkit",
      "Logic bomb",
      "Trojan"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Rootkit is correct. A rootkit is very difficult to detect and often replaces key operating system files with compromised versions, allowing an attacker to access administrative-level functions. Incorrect answers: Worm is incorrect. A worm is a self-propagating piece of malware that can spread without user intervention. Trojan is incorrect. A Trojan is a piece of malware that disguises itself as useful software. Logic bomb is incorrect. A logic bomb is a malicious script that typically activates after a certain date or event."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following wireless attacks is used to exploit a Bluetooth device and copy data from the device?",
    "options": [
      "Bluejacking",
      "Bluesnarfing",
      "Bluebugging",
      "Bluesniffing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Bluesnarfing is correct. Bluesnarfing involves gaining unauthorized access to information on a Bluetooth-enabled device. Incorrect answers: Bluebugging is incorrect. Bluebugging involves an attacker attempting to take control of or use a Bluetooth-enabled cell phone to place calls. Bluejacking is incorrect. Bluejacking is the act of sending unsolicited messages or files to a Bluetooth device. Bluesniffing is incorrect. Bluesniffing is a false, nonexistent term."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes an alternate processing site that is instantly available in the event of a disaster?",
    "options": [
      "Warm site",
      "Reciprocal site",
      "Hot site",
      "Cold site"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Hot site is correct. A hot site is an alternate processing site that can function almost immediately after a disaster and has equipment and data prepositioned, as well as full utilities. Incorrect answers: Reciprocal site is incorrect. Reciprocal sites are alternate locations provided by and in agreement with another organization and are typically co-located with that organization. Cold site is incorrect. Cold sites have only space and utilities available and take longer to activate. Warm site is incorrect. Warm sites have space, utilities, and possibly some equipment and furniture, but still need equipment, personnel, and data transferred, so they cannot be activated instantly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following helps to ensure the information security goal of confidentiality?",
    "options": [
      "Backups",
      "Hashing",
      "Clustering",
      "Encryption"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Encryption is correct. Encryption protects against unauthorized disclosure, ensuring confidentiality. Incorrect answers: Hashing is incorrect. Hashing is used to ensure integrity. Backups is incorrect. Backups help ensure availability. Clustering is incorrect. Clustering helps ensure availability."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have noticed a drop in network performance over the last few hours and would like to monitor the traffic that is entering and leaving the interfaces on your Cisco routers. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "NetFlow",
      "SOAR playbooks",
      "Wireshark",
      "MDM"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: NetFlow is correct. NetFlow is a feature of Cisco routers that allows you to collect and display the packets that enter or leave an interface. Incorrect answers: Wireshark is incorrect. Wireshark is a free packet analyzer that runs on multiple platforms, such as Windows and Linux. MDM is incorrect. Mobile device management (MDM) software is enterprise software used to manage all your mobile devices from a central location. You can deploy policies to the devices that control the features and applications on them. SOAR playbooks is incorrect. SOAR playbooks are used to automate responses to security incidents, and they contain a list of actions that should be taken when a security incident occurs."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are steps of a risk assessment except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Identify recovery procedures.",
      "Mitigate risks or threats.",
      "Identify assets.",
      "Identify risks or threats."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Identify recovery procedures is correct. Identifying recovery procedures is a process that takes place when you're developing a disaster recovery plan, not a risk assessment. Incorrect answers: Identify risks or threats is incorrect. The basic steps of the risk assessment process, in order, are to identify assets, identify threats (risks) against assets, prioritize threats, and mitigate threats. Identify assets is incorrect. The basic steps of the risk assessment process, in order, are to identify assets, identify threats (risks) against assets, prioritize threats, and mitigate threats. Mitigate risks or threats is incorrect. The basic steps of the risk assessment process, in order, are to identify assets, identify threats (risks) against assets, prioritize threats, and mitigate threats."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are working on recovering a database server for some critical applications within the business. The company expected the server to only be down for 30 minutes. What is the disaster recovery term used to describe the company's expectations?",
    "options": [
      "RTO",
      "RPO",
      "DRP",
      "MTBF"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: RTO is correct. The recovery time objective (RTO) is the amount of time expected to recover a system. Incorrect answers: RPO is incorrect. The recovery point objective (RPO) is the point in time we expect a system to be recovered to. MTBF is incorrect. Mean time between failure (MTBF) is the amount of time between occurrences of a device or system failing. DRP is incorrect. A disaster recovery plan is a step-by-step document that gives details on how to recover a system."
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob logs on to the network and receives a message indicating that patches are not up to date and that he cannot be granted access to the network until patches are updated. What network feature is responsible for the message?",
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "NAT",
      "TPM",
      "NAC"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: NAC is correct. Network access control (NAC) can be used to prevent hosts from connecting to the network unless they meet certain security requirements, such as patch level, up-to-date antivirus signatures, and so forth. Incorrect answers: NAT is incorrect. NAT is used to hide the internal network scheme from the outside world and give Internet access to systems on the internal network that use private IP addresses. VPN is incorrect. A VPN is used to create an encrypted tunnel between two points across an untrusted network such as the Internet. TPM is incorrect. Trusted Platform Module (TPM) is a computer chip on a system that stores the cryptographic keys used to encrypt data."
  },
  {
    "question": "What can be done to determine whether users and computing equipment are compliant with corporate security policies?",
    "options": [
      "Set file permissions.",
      "Conduct routine audits.",
      "Use chain of custody.",
      "Use incident response."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Conduct routine audits is correct. Routine audits will reveal noncompliance, or policy violations, of established security policies. Incorrect answers: Set file permissions is incorrect. Setting file permissions secures files but does not reveal if policies are being adhered to (although checking how file permissions are set is related to corporate security policies). Use chain of custody is incorrect. Chain of custody refers to the thorough and secure handling of evidence; this is adhered to for legal reasons and is does not check policy compliance. Use incident response is incorrect. Incident response outlines which tasks are performed when an incident occurs, but it is not related to policy compliance."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of malware is used to allow the attacker to establish a connection to the victim's system and then run remote commands against that system?",
    "options": [
      "RAT",
      "Worm",
      "Logic bomb",
      "Ransomware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: RAT is correct. A remote access Trojan (RAT) is malicious software that the user is tricked into installing, which then opens a back door for the attacker to gain access to the system remotely at a later time. Incorrect answers: Worm is incorrect. A worm is a virus that self replicates, typically across the network or via USB drives. Ransomware is incorrect. Ransomware is malware that encrypts your drive, and then the attacker asks for money in order for you to receive the decryption key. Logic bomb is incorrect. A logic bomb is malware that is triggered by a specific date or event."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for a common attack against web applications where database code is inputted to manipulate the system?",
    "options": [
      "SQL injection",
      "XML injection",
      "Directory traversal",
      "Cross-site scripting"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SQL injection is correct. SQL injection is a common attack on databases through a web-based form, where the attacker injects SQL commands into the form input. Incorrect answers: Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting allows client-side scripts to be run on a web site. XML injection is incorrect. XML injection is an attack that injects faulty or malicious XML code into an XML statement. Directory traversal is incorrect. Directory traversal is the ability to search a web server's directories and files."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the best way to prevent cross-site scripting attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Require certificate-based authentication for web site access.",
      "Restrict CGI script execution.",
      "Validate the input into a web site for illegal characters in a particular field.",
      "Block ports 443 and 80 on the firewall."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Validate the input into a web site for illegal characters in a particular field is correct. Validating the input into a web site form for illegal characters in a field is the best choice for preventing cross-site scripting (XSS) attacks. Incorrect answers: Block ports 443 and 80 on the firewall is incorrect. Blocking ports 443 and 80 will make the site unusable, as these are the typical ports used to access web sites. Require certificate-based authentication for web site access is incorrect. Requiring certificate-based authentication will not prevent cross-site scripting attacks and is an unnecessary measure. Restrict CGI script execution is incorrect. CGI is not a method used for cross-site scripting attacks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager would like to automate mitigation steps in response to attacks on company systems. What tool would you use to automate actions to take in response to a security incident?",
    "options": [
      "DLP",
      "SOAR playbook",
      "NetFlow",
      "MDM"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SOAR playbook is correct. SOAR playbooks are used to automate responses to security incidents and contain a list of actions that should be taken when a security incident occurs. Incorrect answers: MDM is incorrect. Mobile device management (MDM) software is enterprise software used to manage all of your mobile devices from a central location. You can deploy policies to the devices that control features and applications on the device. DLP is incorrect. Data loss prevention (DLP) is a technology used to help prevent data leaks or data exfiltration. NetFlow is incorrect. NetFlow is a feature of Cisco routers that allows you to collect and display the packets that enter or leave an interface."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Type I error?",
    "options": [
      "False negative",
      "False acceptance rate",
      "False rejection rate",
      "Crossover error rate"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: False rejection rate is correct. A false rejection rate (FRR) is a Type I error in biometrics. This also equates to a false positive. Incorrect answers: Crossover error rate is incorrect. The crossover error rate (CER) is the point where the FRR and FAR are equal. False acceptance rate is incorrect. A false acceptance rate (FAR) is a Type II error and is sometimes referred to as a false negative. False negative is incorrect. A false negative is another term for false acceptance rate (FAR) and is incorrect."
  },
  {
    "question": "An attacker posts a malicious document in an online form so that that when someone opens the file, malware is run on their systems that collects their usernames and passwords. What type of attack is this?",
    "options": [
      "Skimming",
      "Credential harvesting",
      "Tailgating",
      "Watering hole"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Credential harvesting is correct. Credential harvesting is when the attacker collects a list of usernames and passwords and then uses those credentials to access systems. Incorrect answers: Watering hole is incorrect. A watering hole attack is when the hacker plants malicious code on a site that the intended victim will visit and run the code. Tailgating is incorrect. Tailgating is when the hacker walks through a secure area by closely following an authorized person who has unlocked the door using their swipe card or passcode. Skimming is incorrect. Skimming is when you swipe your card into a device, the attacker extracts information from the magnetic strip and potentially captures you inputting the PIN for the card."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of sensors works by using an electrical circuit that, when broken, triggers the alarm?",
    "options": [
      "Proximity sensor",
      "Pressure mat sensor",
      "Photoelectric sensor",
      "Closed-circuit sensor"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Closed-circuit sensor is correct. A closed-circuit sensor works by using a closed electrical circuit. If the circuit is open or interrupted, an alarm is triggered. Incorrect answers: Photoelectric sensor is incorrect. With the photoelectric sensor, a beam of light is emitted from a transmitter to a receiver. When an intruder breaks the beam of light, an alarm is triggered. Pressure mat sensor is incorrect. A pressure mat sensor is activated after working hours so that if an intruder enters the facility and walks on the material, the alarm will go off. Proximity sensor is incorrect. A proximity sensor emits a magnetic field that it monitors. When someone approaches, the motion of the intruder changes the field's frequency. The system detects this frequency change and sets off the alarm."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following security measures helps ensure data protection in the event a mobile device is lost or stolen?",
    "options": [
      "Remote wiping",
      "Remote destruction",
      "Remote access",
      "Remote encryption"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Remote wiping is correct. Remote drive or disk wiping is used to ensure data protection and confidentiality on a mobile device in the event it is lost or stolen. Incorrect answers: Remote destruction is incorrect. Remote destruction is an invalid term in this context. Remote access is incorrect. Remote access enables a remote user to authenticate to and access an organization's private network. Remote encryption is incorrect. There is no such technology referred to as remote encryption."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are security measures used to harden a host except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Opening unused ports",
      "Uninstalling unnecessary applications",
      "Installing security patches",
      "Updating antivirus signatures"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct  answer: Opening unused ports is correct. Opening unused ports would increase the attack surface on a host. Closing unused ports is considered a good hardening practice. Incorrect answers: Uninstalling unnecessary applications is incorrect. When hardening a system, you would uninstall unnecessary applications. Installing security patches is incorrect. When hardening a system, you would apply any security patches. Updating antivirus signatures is incorrect. When hardening a system, you would updated the virus definitions."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are reviewing the logs on your web server and notice that there are a number of logon attempts that have failed using different usernames each time, but the same password was attempted. What type of attack is occurring?",
    "options": [
      "Dictionary",
      "Password spraying",
      "Smishing",
      "Credential harvesting"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Password spraying is correct. Password spraying is when the same common password is tried against a number of user accounts. Incorrect answers: Credential harvesting is incorrect. Credential harvesting is when the attacker collects a list of usernames and passwords and then uses those credentials to access systems. Dictionary is incorrect. A dictionary attack is a form of password attack where usernames and passwords are read from a file and used to try to authenticate to a system. Smishing is incorrect. Smishing is a form of phishing attack that involves the hacker sending text messages to a potential victim."
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the employees within your company has been involved in suspicious activity. You have seized the computer and would like to create a forensics image of the drive to perform an analysis on. What tool would you use to create an image of the drive?",
    "options": [
      "dd",
      "Memdump",
      "WinHex",
      "Autopsy"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: dd is correct. dd is a program used to create a forensic image of a hard drive or an image of memory. Incorrect answers: Autopsy is incorrect. Autopsy is used to analyze the contents of an image after it is created. WinHex is incorrect. WinHex is a hex editor that can be used to view the raw data of files, including the file header. Memdump is incorrect. Memdump is a utility used to copy the contents of memory to a file so that it can be analyzed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following keys is used for nonrepudiation?",
    "options": [
      "Public key",
      "Hash",
      "Private key",
      "Symmetric key"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Private key is correct. The private key, when used for nonrepudiation, is used to encrypt text that anyone who possesses the public key can decrypt. This ensures that only the person owning the private key could have encrypted it—that he or she is the one who performed the action. Used in this scenario, this does not guarantee confidentiality, but it does provide for nonrepudiation. Incorrect answers: Symmetric key is incorrect. A symmetric key does not provide for nonrepudiation because it cannot be used to guarantee who sent a message or performed an action. The symmetric key is used to encrypt content. Public key is incorrect. A public key can be in the possession of anyone and is used in this case to verify that the private key was used to encrypt the text for nonrepudiation. Hash is incorrect. Hashes do not provide for nonrepudiation because they cannot be used to guarantee who sent a message or performed an action. They are used to verify the integrity of data."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization has a number of embedded systems across the enterprise. What is considered one of the security risks with embedded systems?",
    "options": [
      "Use of symmetric encryption",
      "Inability to patch",
      "Less powerful CPU",
      "Use of WPA2"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Inability to patch is correct. One of the security risks with embedded systems is if the vendor does not provide a way to patch the embedded system to remove vulnerabilities that are discovered over time. Incorrect answers: Less powerful CPU is incorrect. Having a less powerful CPU would not present a security risk. Use of symmetric encryption is incorrect. Using symmetric encryption would not present a security risk. Use of WPA2 is incorrect. Using wireless encryption such as WPA2 is an important security feature for wireless communication if the embedded system is using wireless communication."
  },
  {
    "question": "When you're backing up data to tape, which type of backup does not clear or reset the archive bit on a file?",
    "options": [
      "Full",
      "Differential",
      "Volume",
      "Incremental"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Differential is correct. A differential backup will back up all data that has been added or changed since the last full backup. It does not reset the archive bit on a file. It is used, in conjunction with full backups, to restore systems quickly if needed, since only the full backup and the very last differential backup created must be restored. Incorrect answers: Full is incorrect. Full backups clear the archive bit on all files. Incremental is incorrect. Incremental backups clear the archive bit after backing up a file. Volume is incorrect. Volume backups is an incorrect term for this context."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements are correct with regard to the concepts of fail-secure and fail-safe? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "A fail-secure device responds by making sure the device is using a secure state when a failure occurs.",
      "A fail-safe device responds by not doing anything to cause harm when the failure occurs.",
      "A fail-safe device responds by making sure the device is using a secure state when a failure occurs.",
      "A fail-secure device responds by not doing anything to cause harm when the failure occurs."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0,
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: A fail-safe device responds by not doing anything to cause harm when the failure occurs and a fail-secure device responds by making sure the device is using a secure state when a failure occurs are correct. A fail-safe device responds by not doing anything to cause harm when the failure occurs. A fail-secure device responds by making sure the device is using a secure state when a failure occurs. Incorrect answers: A fail-secure device responds by not doing anything to cause harm when the failure occurs is incorrect. This is the definition of fail-safe, not fail-secure. A fail-safe device responds by making sure the device is using a secure state when a failure occurs is incorrect."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following identifies a risk to wireless networks?",
    "options": [
      "Evil twin",
      "MSSP",
      "COPE",
      "CASB"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Evil twin is correct. An evil twin attack is when the hacker sets up a fake access point that appears to be the legitimate access point for clients to connect to. Clients connect to the hacker's fake access point, thinking it is a valid wireless network, and all data sent on this wireless network will be sent to the hacker's system, allowing the hacker to capture and read all the data. Incorrect answers: COPE is incorrect. Corporate owned personally enabled (COPE) is a mobile device deployment model where the company supplies the device to the user. Because the company owns the device, it is managed by the IT department, but the company allows and promotes personal usage of the device as well. MSSP is incorrect. A managed security service provider (MSSP) is a cloud service provider used for security configuration of your cloud environment, monitoring of activity, management of intrusion detection systems (IDSs) and firewalls, patch management, responding to security incidents, and performing security assessments within the organization. CASB is incorrect. A cloud access security broker (CASB) is a security service that sits between your on-premises environment and your cloud provider's environment. The CASB allows you to define security policies that apply to network traffic flowing outside your current on-premises environment to the cloud."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered part of AAA services except for which one?",
    "options": [
      "Authentication",
      "Authorization",
      "Accounting",
      "Availability"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Availability is correct. Availability has nothing to do with AAA services and is a part of the CIA triad. Incorrect answers: Accounting is incorrect. Accounting is part of AAA and is used to ensure accountability of actions through auditing and logging. Authentication is incorrect. Authentication is the first part of AAA and is used to verify the logon credentials of individuals attempting to access the system. Authorization is incorrect. After an individual is authenticated, authorization kicks in as they try to access resources on the system. Authorization is allowing or denying the request to access a resource."
  },
  {
    "question": "What security solution would you recommend to your manager to reduce the risk of sensitive data being accidentally leaked or stolen?",
    "options": [
      "MSSP",
      "DLP",
      "SPIM",
      "XSS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DLP is correct. Data loss prevention (DLP) is a set of technologies that prevent sensitive data from being leaked outside the organization. For example, DLP solutions can prevent sensitive data from being sent in an e-mail or copied to a USB drive. Incorrect answers: MSSP is incorrect. A managed security service provider (MSSP) is a cloud service provider used for security configuration of your cloud environment, monitoring of activity, management of intrusion detection systems (IDSs) and firewalls, patch management, responding to security incidents, and performing security assessments within the organization. XSS is incorrect. Cross-site scripting (XSS) is when the attacker submits script code as input into a site, typically so the code is stored in the back-end database and then run by another visitor when they view the page. SPIM is incorrect. SPIM is short for spam over instant messaging."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has subscribed to a cloud service where your employees access the application from a web browser. Your admin team does not have to install any software or manage updates for the software. What type of cloud service are you using?",
    "options": [
      "IaaS",
      "XaaS",
      "PaaS",
      "SaaS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SaaS is correct. In the Software as a Service (SaaS) cloud model, an application is provided to the client without the client needing to install the application. Common examples of SaaS are Hotmail, Gmail, and Microsoft 365. Incorrect answers: PaaS is incorrect. With the Platform as a Service (PaaS) cloud model, the cloud service provider (CSP) supplies the runtime environment and development tools to create applications in the cloud. IaaS is incorrect. With Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), the CSP gives the customer a way to create a virtual data center, including creating virtual networks, storage, and virtual machines. XaaS is incorrect. Any other cloud solutions fall into Anything as a Service (XaaS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attacks involves sending ICMP packets from a spoofed IP address to the network's broadcast address?",
    "options": [
      "RAT",
      "Botnet",
      "Smurf attack",
      "Watering hole attack"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Smurf attack is correct. A smurf attack is a type of ICMP attack where large amounts of ping packets are sent from a spoofed IP address on the network to the network broadcast address, causing many replies back to the victim and possibly bringing about a denial of service. A smurf attack is an example of a DDoS attack. Incorrect answers: RAT is incorrect. A remote access Trojan (RAT) is malicious software that the user typically installs without knowing it, such as by installing a game from the Internet or by running a program that was e-mailed to them that is malicious software. The RAT program then opens a back door for the hacker to gain access to the system remotely at a later time. Botnet is incorrect. A botnet is a group of compromised systems that the hacker has control over and uses to attack a victim's system. Watering hole attack is incorrect. A watering hole attack is when the hacker determines a site you may want to visit and then compromises the site by planting viruses or malicious code on it. When you visit the site (which you trust), you are then infected with the virus."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following protocols is a more secure version of the SSL protocol?",
    "options": [
      "RSA",
      "TLS",
      "AES",
      "SSH"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: TLS is correct. Transport Layer Security (TLS) is considered a strong replacement for SSL. Incorrect answers: SSH is incorrect. SSH is a secure replacement for Telnet and other nonsecure protocols. AES is incorrect. AES is a symmetric algorithm that replaces DES. RSA is incorrect. RSA is an asymmetric algorithm used in public key cryptography."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following application attacks allows attackers to inject client-side script into web pages viewed by other users?",
    "options": [
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "XML injection",
      "SQL injection",
      "Buffer overflow"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Cross-site scripting is correct. Cross-site scripting (XSS) enables attackers to inject client-side scripts into web pages viewed by others. Incorrect answers: XML injection is incorrect. XML injection occurs when malicious XML code is inserted into an XML statement. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection involves inserting faulty SQL input commands into a site that connects to a database, producing unintended results or returning privileged information. Buffer overflow is incorrect. A buffer overflow takes advantage of programming flaws that occur when data overwrites a program's allocated memory address and enables arbitrary code to be executed in that address."
  },
  {
    "question": "Backing up the current state of the system is a critical step in which of the following processes?",
    "options": [
      "Incident response",
      "Data classification",
      "Forensics analysis",
      "Change management"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Change management is correct. Change management is a process that should be followed when performing any changes to systems on the network. One of the steps to making a change to a system is to back up the system before you implement the change so that if there is a problem, you can always revert to the state before the change was made. Incorrect answers: Forensics analysis is incorrect. Forensics analysis is performed when there is a security incident that needs to be investigated. Incident response is incorrect. Incident response is the process followed when a security incident occurs. Data classification is incorrect. Data classification is a system used to identify different types of data on the network and a way to associate that data with security clearance levels."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following risk mitigation strategies means that you do not implement any solution to protect against the threat because you are satisfied that the chances of the threat occurring and the impact of the threat do not warrant the cost of implementing a security control?",
    "options": [
      "Risk acceptance",
      "Risk mitigation",
      "Risk avoidance",
      "Risk transference"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Risk acceptance is correct. Risk acceptance means that you do not implement any solution to protect against the threat because you are satisfied that the chances of the threat occurring and the impact of the threat do not warrant the cost of implementing a security control. Incorrect answers: Risk mitigation is incorrect. Risk mitigation involves implementing controls to reduce the risk. Risk transference is incorrect. Risk transference means to have someone else assume the risk, as in the case of purchasing insurance or outsourcing. Risk avoidance is incorrect. Risk avoidance simply means to not perform any activity that incurs the risk in the first place."
  },
  {
    "question": "Sara, the IT manager within your organization, is looking to secure the VoIP traffic on your network and has assigned the task to you. Which of the following protocols would you use?",
    "options": [
      "SIP",
      "RDP",
      "SRTP",
      "RTP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SRTP is correct. Secure Real-time Transport Protocol (SRTP) is the secure version of RTP that is used to encrypt VoIP traffic. Incorrect answers: RDP is incorrect. RDP is used for remote desktop access to a system across a TCP/IP network. RTP is incorrect. RTP is an unsecure protocol used for VoIP traffic. SIP is incorrect. SIP is an unsecure protocol used for VoIP traffic."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager has read a lot about server virtualization and is wondering if there are any security benefits to using it. What are the benefits you could mention?",
    "options": [
      "Fewer systems to physically secure",
      "Larger hardware footprint",
      "Decentralized server security",
      "More work required to harden systems"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Fewer systems to physically secure is correct. Virtualization results in fewer physical systems (and less hardware) that must be secured. Incorrect answers: Larger hardware footprint is incorrect. Having a larger hardware footprint does not offer any benefits, security or otherwise, of virtualization. Decentralized server security is incorrect. Having decentralized server security does not offer any benefits, security or otherwise, of virtualization. More work required to harden systems is incorrect. Having more work to harden systems does not offer any benefits, security or otherwise, of virtualization."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have created a forensic image of a suspect's hard drive and would now like to perform the analysis on the drive. What tool would you use?",
    "options": [
      "dd",
      "nmap",
      "Memdump",
      "Autopsy"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Autopsy is correct. Autopsy is a free tool used for forensics analysis. Incorrect answers: dd is incorrect. dd is used to create a forensics image of a hard drive or memory. Memdump is incorrect. Memdump is used to dump the contents of memory to a file so that it can be analyzed. nmap is incorrect. nmap is a port scanner that can be used to identify ports open on a system."
  },
  {
    "question": "While performing a penetration test on your company systems, you have discovered that code within a virtual machine is able to manipulate the host system. What would you do to protect the system?",
    "options": [
      "Install a firewall on the host system.",
      "Patch the host system.",
      "Install a firewall in the VM.",
      "Patch the VM."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Patch the host system is correct. VM escape is a security risk to virtualization environments that are unpatched. VM escape allows an application to access the host system from within the VM. Incorrect answers: Patch the VM is incorrect. You would not patch the VM in this scenario because the vulnerability exists with the virtualization platform. Install a firewall in the VM is incorrect. Installing a firewall will not help because the problem is that a vulnerability exists in the virtualization platform. Install a firewall on the host system is incorrect. Installing a firewall will not help because the problem is that a vulnerability exists in the virtualization platform."
  },
  {
    "question": "Look at the following output of a script being executed. What type of attack is being performed?```",
    "options": [
      "root@kali:`# attack.py 10.0.0.100 443",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: admin",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: pass",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: Pa$$w0rd",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: toor",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: root password: admin",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: root password: pass",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: root password: Pa$$w0rd",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: root password: toor",
      "[-] Success!  Username: root and password: toor is valid! ```",
      "Dictionary",
      "Credential harvesting",
      "Pass the hash",
      "Password spraying"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      17
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Dictionary is correct. A dictionary attack is a form of password attack that involves the same username being used with a number of potential passwords. Incorrect answers: Password spraying is incorrect. Password spraying is a password attack that involves different usernames being used, but the same password is attempted with each username. Credential harvesting is incorrect. Credential harvesting is when the attacker collects usernames and passwords. Pass the hash is incorrect. Pass the hash is when the attacker obtains password hashes from a previous attack and then tries to use a password hash as the value of a password instead of trying to crack the password."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following networking technologies provides for local area network segregation using switches?",
    "options": [
      "VLAN",
      "Virtualization",
      "RADIUS",
      "VPN"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct  answer: VLAN is correct. VLANs (virtual LANs) provide for local area network segmentation and separation and are implemented on switches. Incorrect answers: RADIUS is incorrect. RADIUS is a remote access authentication technology. Virtualization is incorrect. Virtualization refers to the creation and management of virtual hosts running in a virtualized environment. VPN is incorrect. VPN is a secure remote access technology."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of study reveals the effect that realized threats could have on the operation of an organization?",
    "options": [
      "Business impact analysis",
      "Security audit",
      "Incident response",
      "Risk analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Business impact analysis is correct. A business impact analysis identifies how personnel, data systems, clients, and revenue will be affected if a threat is realized. Incorrect answers: Risk analysis is incorrect. A risk analysis is conducted before a business impact analysis; otherwise, the threats would not yet have been identified. Incident response is incorrect. Incident response defines what is to be done when a threat is realized, but it does not specify how regular business operations are affected. Security audit is incorrect. Security audits identify vulnerabilities and policy noncompliance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following protocols uses IPSec to ensure confidentiality?",
    "options": [
      "SSL",
      "L2TP",
      "PPP",
      "PPTP"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: L2TP is correct. IPSec provides encryption services for L2TP when used in a VPN implementation. Incorrect answers: PPP is incorrect. PPP does not use IPSec for encryption. PPTP is incorrect. PPTP does not use IPSec for encryption. SSL is incorrect. SSL does not use IPSec for encryption services."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company deals with a wealth of sensitive information. Your manager would like to reduce the risk of data exfiltration from company systems. What would you recommend?",
    "options": [
      "Enable a host-based firewall.",
      "Patch the systems.",
      "Disable wireless networking.",
      "Disable USB ports."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Disable USB ports is correct. One of the techniques to prevent data exfiltration, which is the unauthorized copying of information, is to disable USB ports on the system so that a USB drive cannot be connected to it. Another technique is to use data loss prevention (DLP) solutions, which would block leaking information through USB drives and e-mail. Incorrect answers: Enable a host-based firewall is incorrect. Enabling a firewall on the system will not stop copying files to a local USB drive or sending a file through e-mail, which are common techniques used to copy data. Disable wireless networking is incorrect. Wireless networking is not a factor for using data exfiltration techniques, such as copying files to a USB drive or sending files through e-mail (that is, if there is a wired connection). Patch the systems is incorrect. Patching the systems is how we reduce the number of vulnerabilities on them. Data exfiltration is more of a user problem than a vulnerability problem."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following items help(s) support the concept of accountability?",
    "options": [
      "Encryption",
      "Permissions",
      "Audit logs",
      "Hashing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Audit logs is correct. Auditing and the logs that result from it support accountability by showing who performed which actions. This helps make people accountable for their actions. Incorrect answers: Permissions is incorrect. Permissions support authorization, not accountability. Hashing is incorrect. Hashing supports the concept of integrity. Encryption is incorrect. Encryption supports the concept of confidentiality."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager is interested in implementing a strong authentication scheme. Which of the following is considered the strongest authentication?",
    "options": [
      "PIN",
      "Username/password",
      "Fingerprint",
      "Iris scan"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Iris scan is correct. Out of the choices given, an iris scan is the strongest method of authentication, as these patterns are very unique to individuals. Of all of the biometric authentication methods, including voiceprints and fingerprints, iris scans are the most accurate. Incorrect answers: Username/password is incorrect. Username and password combinations are not considered strong methods of authentication. PIN is incorrect. Using just a PIN is not considered a strong method of authentication. Fingerprint is incorrect. Fingerprints are not considered as strong a method of biometric authentication as iris scans."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of cipher involves replacing one character for another?",
    "options": [
      "Transposition",
      "Asymmetric",
      "Hashing",
      "Substitution"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Substitution is correct. A substitution cipher involves substituting one character for another. Incorrect answers: Asymmetric is incorrect. Asymmetric is a category of encryption methods and algorithms. Hashing is incorrect. Hashing provides for a one-way hash, or message digest, of a variable block of text. Transposition is incorrect. A transposition cipher rearranges characters in a message rather than substituting them."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attacks seeks to introduce erroneous or malicious entries into a server's hostname-to-IP address cache or zone file?",
    "options": [
      "Session hijacking",
      "ARP poisoning",
      "DNS poisoning",
      "DHCP poisoning"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DNS poisoning is correct. DNS poisoning involves introducing false entries into a DNS server's zone file, or a server's hostname-to-IP address cache, with the intent of misdirecting a DNS resolution request to a different server or site. Incorrect answers: ARP poisoning is incorrect. ARP poisoning involves introducing false entries into a host's ARP cache, which maps MAC addresses to IP addresses. DHCP poisoning is incorrect. DHCP poisoning is a false term, although there are several known DHCP network attacks. Session hijacking is incorrect. Session hijacking involves intercepting and taking over an in-progress communications session between two hosts."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of malware is designed to activate after a predetermined amount of time or upon a specific event or date?",
    "options": [
      "Trojan",
      "Rootkit",
      "Logic bomb",
      "Adware"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Logic bomb is correct. A logic bomb is a type of malware, usually very difficult to detect, that is designed to activate only after a specific time has passed or a specific date or event has occurred. Incorrect answers: Rootkit is incorrect. A rootkit is software installed on the system by the hacker that is typically hidden from the administrator and that gives the hacker privileged access to the system. Trojan is incorrect. A Trojan virus is a virus that presents itself as a legitimate program, but instead it gives the hacker access to the system once it is installed. Adware is incorrect. Adware is software that automatically loads advertisements on the screen, typically in the form of a pop-up window."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your manager would like to use a cloud service that allows you to create a virtual data center, including creating virtual machines for your company servers. What cloud service should you use?",
    "options": [
      "PaaS",
      "XaaS",
      "IaaS",
      "SaaS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: IaaS is correct. With Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), the cloud service provider (CSP) gives the customer a way to create a virtual data center, including creating virtual networks, storage, and virtual machines. Incorrect answers: PaaS is incorrect. With the Platform as a Service (PaaS) cloud model, the CSP supplies the runtime environment and development tools to create applications in the cloud. SaaS is incorrect. In the Software as a Service (SaaS) cloud model, an application is provided to the client without the client needing to install the application. Common examples of SaaS are Hotmail, Gmail, and Microsoft 365. XaaS is incorrect. Any other cloud solutions fall into Anything as a Service (XaaS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A technician analyzes historical web server performance and determines there is a 7 percent chance per year that a server outage will occur for three hours. The web server hosts an e-commerce site that generates on average $350 per hour. What is the ALE (annual loss expectancy) value?",
    "options": [
      "$73.50",
      "$350",
      "$8.16",
      "$15,000"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: $73.50 is correct. The SLE (single loss expectancy) value of $350 is multiplied by the amount of downtime (three hours), which is multiplied by the ARO (annual rate of occurrence) value of 7 percent to arrive at $73.50. This is the dollar amount represented per annum by this risk. So, for example, spending $500 per annum to minimize this risk is not justified. Incorrect answers: $15,000, $8.16, and $350 are incorrect. They were not calculated as per ALE = SLE × ARO."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have performed a vulnerability scan on a production server and receive the following results: Vulnerability 1: CVSS 4.5 Vulnerability 2: CVSS 9 Vulnerability 3: CVSS 2 Vulnerability 4: CVSS 4 Which vulnerability is the most critical?",
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability 2",
      "Vulnerability 1",
      "Vulnerability 3",
      "Vulnerability 4"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Vulnerability 2 is correct. Vulnerability scan results are rated based on the Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) score. The score is a number from 1 to 10, where the lower the number, the less critical the vulnerability is. Incorrect answers: Vulnerability 1 is incorrect. The score is based on a number from 1 to 10, where the lower the number, the less critical the vulnerability is. Vulnerability 3 is incorrect. The score is based on a number from 1 to 10, where the lower the number, the less critical the vulnerability is. Vulnerability 4 is incorrect. The score is based on a number from 1 to 10, where the lower the number, the less critical the vulnerability is."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following encryption technologies can be used to encrypt individual files?",
    "options": [
      "SSL",
      "WPA",
      "EFS",
      "TLS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: EFS is correct. The Encrypting File System (EFS) is a Windows technology that allows a user to encrypt individual files on an NTFS-formatted hard disk. Incorrect answers: SSL is incorrect. SSL is used to encrypt communication, such as web communication with HTTPS. TLS is incorrect. TLS is the replacement of SSL and is used to encrypt communication, such as web communication using HTTPS. WPA is incorrect. WPA is one of the protocols that can be used to encrypt wireless communication."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following protocols is considered a secure replacement for Telnet?",
    "options": [
      "TLS",
      "SSL",
      "SSH",
      "RLOGIN"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SSH is correct. Secure Shell (SSH) is considered a secure replacement for Telnet. Incorrect answers: TLS is incorrect. TLS is a secure session protocol used in HTTPS traffic and is the successor of SSL. RLOGIN is incorrect. RLOGIN is an older, nonsecure protocol. SSL is incorrect. SSL is a secure session protocol used in HTTPS traffic that is slowly being replaced by TLS."
  },
  {
    "question": "Tanya is the network administrator for a midsize company and needs to apply updates to a number of mission-critical systems on the network. What mitigation technique should she use to reduce the risk to the systems?",
    "options": [
      "Change management",
      "Incident response",
      "Forensics analysis",
      "Data classification"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Change management is correct. Change management is a process that should be followed when performing any changes to systems on the network. The change management process helps reduce risk against your assets because it involves having a plan for implementing changes. Incorrect answers: Forensics analysis is incorrect. Forensics analysis is performed when there is a security incident that needs to be investigated. Incident response is incorrect. Incident response is the process followed when a security incident occurs. Data classification is incorrect. Data classification is a system used to identify different types of data on the network and a way to associate that data with security clearance levels."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of two-factor authentication?",
    "options": [
      "Username and password",
      "Smartcard and PIN",
      "Password and PIN",
      "Fingerprint and retina"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Smartcard and PIN is correct. Use of a smartcard and PIN involves the use of two factors: something you have and something you know. Incorrect answers: Fingerprint and retina is incorrect. Using a fingerprint and retina scan are both forms of biometrics; therefore, this is only single-factor authentication (both are examples of something you are). Password and PIN is incorrect. Knowing a password and a PIN is an example of single-factor authentication because they are both examples of something you know. Username and password is incorrect. Knowing a username and password is single-factor authentication because they are both examples of something you know."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are monitoring activity to your web server and notice a request with this URL: http://10.0.0.3/scripts/..%c0%af../winnt/system32/cmd.exe?/c+dir+c: What type of attack is it?",
    "options": [
      "Directory traversal",
      "SQL injection",
      "XSS",
      "CSRF"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Directory traversal is correct. Directory traversal attacks use ../.. in the URL, which allows the hacker to navigate backward in the file system of the web site to access sensitive files on the system. Incorrect answers: XSS is incorrect. Cross-site scripting (XSS) is when the attacker submits script code as input into a site, typically so the code is stored in the back-end database and then run by another visitor when they view the page. CSRF is incorrect. Cross-site request forgery (CSRF) is when the attacker tricks a person into clicking a link that makes a call to another site that the user is already authenticated to. For example, the link may change the user's password on the other site. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection is when the attacker inputs database code as input into an application in order to manipulate the system or the data in the database."
  },
  {
    "question": "Look at the following command output. What type of attack is being performed?```",
    "options": [
      "root@kali:`# attack.py 10.0.0.100 443",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: 8846F7EAEE8FB117AD06BDD830B7586C",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: 92937945B518814341DE3F726500D4FF",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: AFC44EE7351D61D00698796DA06B1EBF",
      "[-] Failed.",
      "[+] Attempting username: admin password: 209C6174DA490CAEB422F3FA5A7AE634",
      "[-] Success!  Username: admin and password: 209C6174DA490CAEB422F3FA5A7AE634 is valid! ```",
      "Pass the hash",
      "Denial of service",
      "Phishing",
      "Credential harvesting"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      9
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Pass the hash is correct. Pass the hash is when the attacker obtains password hashes from a previous attack and then tries to use a password hash as the value of a password instead of trying to crack the password. Incorrect answers: Credential harvesting is incorrect. Credential harvesting is when the attacker collects usernames and passwords. Denial of service is incorrect. Denial of service (DoS) attacks are when the hacker prevents a system from performing its function, typically by overwhelming the system with requests. Phishing is incorrect. Phishing is when an attacker tries to trick a user into compromising security, typically by sending an e-mail message with a link to a fake site that tricks the user into attempting to log in. Meanwhile, the hacker is recording the username and password information."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are performing an internal company investigation involving an employee's laptop. You have seized the laptop. What should you use before capturing an image of the suspect's laptop drive?",
    "options": [
      "IPFIX",
      "Runbook",
      "dd",
      "Write blocker"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Write blocker is correct. You should have a write blocker connected to the forensics workstation so that the investigation system does not alter the suspect's drive. Incorrect answers: dd is incorrect. dd is software used to create an image of the suspect's drive. IPFIX is incorrect. Internet Protocol Flow Information eXport (IPFIX) is an RFC standard for monitoring traffic that enters or leaves an interface. Runbook is incorrect. SOAR runbooks are documents that contain procedures on how to perform IT tasks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Sara is the senior security administrator for the company. You inform Sara that you would like to prevent employees from sending sensitive company information to their personal e-mail accounts. What technology should Sara suggest?",
    "options": [
      "DLP",
      "CRL",
      "TPM",
      "NAC"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: DLP is correct. Data loss prevention (DLP) is a set of technologies that can be used to prevent data leakage outside your organization. Incorrect answers: NAC is incorrect. Network access control (NAC) is used to enforce that clients are of good health before they can connect to the network. CRL is incorrect. A certificate revocation list (CRL) is a list of certificates that have been revoked. TPM is incorrect. A Trusted Platform Module (TPM) is a chip that contains encryption keys."
  },
  {
    "question": "What key element in security policies must be present in order for the policies to be effective?",
    "options": [
      "Technology standards",
      "Implementation guidelines",
      "Technical procedures",
      "Management buy-in and enforcement"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Management buy-in and enforcement is correct. For policies to be effective, management must approve and support them, including ensuring enforcement. Incorrect answers: Technical procedures is incorrect. Procedures, standards, and guidelines serve to support policies by describing the “how” and “to what degree” aspects of policy implementation. Technology standards is incorrect. Procedures, standards, and guidelines serve to support policies by describing the “how” and “to what degree” aspects of policy implementation. Implementation guidelines is incorrect. Procedures, standards, and guidelines serve to support policies by describing the “how” and “to what degree” aspects of policy implementation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of risk analysis is subjective and can involve assigning values from a scale you create?",
    "options": [
      "Qualitative",
      "Quantitative",
      "Consultative",
      "Probabilistic"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Qualitative is correct. A qualitative risk assessment determines the risk and mitigation techniques without actually calculating the loss as a dollar figure. With qualitative risk analysis, you create a scale and rate each threat based on the values in the scale, such as low, medium, and high. Incorrect answers: Consultative is incorrect. Consultative is not a valid risk assessment technique. Probabilistic is incorrect. Probabilistic is not a valid risk assessment technique. Quantitative is incorrect. Quantitative risk analysis involves determining dollar amounts for loss and mitigation."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the network administrator for a small company that would like to monitor network traffic and be alerted of any suspicious traffic. What type of device should you use?",
    "options": [
      "HIPS",
      "Firewall",
      "Spam filter",
      "NIPS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: NIPS is correct. A network-based intrusion prevention system (NIPS) can detect suspicious activity across the network and send notification or take corrective action. Also note that a network-based intrusion detection system (NIDS) can also detect suspicious activity and send an alert, but it cannot take correction action. Incorrect answers: Spam filter is incorrect. A spam filter will block unsolicited e-mail messages from entering your organization. HIPS is incorrect. A host-based intrusion prevention system (HIPS) will detect suspicious activity on a single system. Firewall is incorrect. A firewall is used to control traffic entering and leaving the network."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are performing a site survey of a company location and notice that one of the wireless access points is on top of a bookshelf that is located by the outer wall of the building. What is the security concern?",
    "options": [
      "Interference",
      "Damage due to falling",
      "Wireless network access by persons outside the building",
      "Signal degradation"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Wireless network access by persons outside the building is correct. Because of the placement near the outer wall, the wireless access point's signals could be detected outside the building and could allow an unauthorized user to eavesdrop on or use the connection. Incorrect answers: Damage due to falling is incorrect. Damage due to falling is a concern, but not the most immediate security concern. Interference is incorrect. Interference could happen only if other wireless devices are nearby that transmit on frequencies close to the one the access point uses. Interference is a performance concern but not typically a security concern, unless it is malicious in nature and seeks to cause a denial of service condition. Signal degradation is incorrect. Signal degradation for the rest of the facility would not be caused by the placement of the access point next to the outer wall."
  },
  {
    "question": "You have a number of salespeople who travel for work. Your manager is concerned that when employees connect their mobile devices to charging stations in airports, they will get hit with malicious code. What protection mechanism would you use to reduce the risk of a security incident to the mobile devices?",
    "options": [
      "USB data blocker",
      "Air gap",
      "Mantrap",
      "Cable lock"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: USB data blocker is correct. A USB data blocker should be given to employees who are connecting their mobile devices to charging stations in public places. Incorrect answers: Mantrap is incorrect. A mantrap is used to prevent tailgating. Cable lock is incorrect. A cable lock should be used with laptops and other mobile equipment to lock those items in place to prevent them from being stolen. Air gap is incorrect. An air gap is an area that separates two different networks. For example, highly secure environments typically have a secret network that has no connections to the corporate network or LAN. This means an air gap exists between the secret network and other networks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has an e-commerce web site that stores and reuses the credit card numbers of its customers. Which of the following is a recommended security strategy for securely reusing credit card numbers?",
    "options": [
      "Tokenization",
      "Rights management",
      "Hashing",
      "Masking"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Tokenization is correct. The tokenization of credit card numbers should be used so that the credit card numbers can be reused in a secure manner. Tokenization is when sensitive data is stored with a token service instead of with the application data with which the sensitive data is used. The token service creates a random string that maps to the credit card number in the token database. The application then uses the random string to represent the credit card number. Incorrect answers: Hashing is incorrect. Hashing is used to ensure data integrity, not confidentiality. Masking is incorrect. Masking is when the application covers up the data onscreen with a character such as an asterisk (*), but the actual data is still stored in the database in plain text. Rights management is incorrect. Rights management is a technology to protect digital content by placing restrictions on the use of the content. For example, a video file can only be viewed for two days, or an e-mail message is not allowed to be printed or forwarded."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following components of risk can be reduced or lowered except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Threats",
      "Impact",
      "Exposure factor",
      "Vulnerabilities"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Threats is correct. Threats such as natural disasters, hackers, and so forth are typically not within the control of the organization and therefore cannot usually be lowered or eliminated. The risk posed by the threat can be reduced using mitigation techniques, but not the threat itself. The strategy is to try to limit the impact of the threat or the damage it can do. Incorrecrt answers: Vulnerabilities is incorrect. Vulnerabilities for an asset can be reduced by implementing security controls. Exposure factor is incorrect. The exposure factor, or percentage of loss, can be lessened by reducing the vulnerability or increasing the protection of an asset. Impact is incorrect. The impact on the organization can be lessened as well by reducing vulnerabilities, better protecting assets, increasing redundancy, and so forth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following steps is the first to be accomplished during a penetration test?",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "Password cracking",
      "Privilege escalation",
      "Obtaining permission for the test"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Obtaining permission for the test is correct. Before beginning any type of penetration test or vulnerability assessment, you must first obtain permission from the responsible system owner to avoid legal or liability issues. Incorrect answers: Port scanning is incorrect. Although you would perform a port scan during a penetration test, it is not the first thing you should do. Privilege escalation is incorrect. Although you may perform privilege escalation during a penetration test, it is not the first thing you should do. Password cracking is incorrect. Although you may perform password attacks during a penetration test, it is not the first thing you should do."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are configuring IPSec on your network and need to allow security association (SA) traffic to pass through the firewall. Which of the following ports does the Internet Key Exchange (IKE) protocol, which is the protocol responsible for the SA setup within IPSec, use?",
    "options": [
      "443",
      "8080",
      "500",
      "22"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: 500 is correct. IKE uses UDP port 500. Incorrect answers: 443 is incorrect. Port 443 is used by SSL. 22 is incorrect. Port 22 is used by SSH. 8080 is incorrect. Port 8080 does not fall into the range of well-known ports (0–1023) but is frequently used by proxy servers and other security devices."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered secure application development practices except which one?",
    "options": [
      "Memory management",
      "Input validation",
      "Elasticity",
      "Error and exception handling"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Elasticity is correct. Elasticity is a benefit of cloud computing, not a secure coding best practice. Elasticity is the concept that additional back-end servers be automatically started during times of high workload and shut down during periods of low activity. Incorrect answers: Input validation is incorrect. Input validation is a secure coding practice that involves checking all input that is received by the application before processing the input. Error and exception handling is incorrect. Error and exception handling is a secure coding practice that involves checking for common errors and handling them in order to prevent an error from occurring. Memory management is incorrect. Memory management is removing unnecessary resources from memory when they are no longer used to help free up memory."
  },
  {
    "question": "The hacker has managed to modify the cache on the system that stores IP addresses and corresponding MAC addresses with inappropriate entries. What type of attack has occurred?",
    "options": [
      "ARP poisoning",
      "DHCP poisoning",
      "VLAN poisoning",
      "DNS poisoning"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: ARP poisoning is correct. ARP poisoning involves introducing false entries into the host's ARP cache, essentially spoofing MAC addresses. Incorrect answers: DNS poisoning is incorrect. DNS poisoning involves introducing false entries into a DNS server's cache or its zone files. DHCP poisoning is incorrect. There is no such attack called DHCP poisoning. VLAN poisoning is incorrect. There is no such attack called VLAN poisoning."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ashlyn, the senior security officer within your organization, has requested that you create a plan for an active security test that tries to bypass the security controls of an asset. What type of test would you plan?",
    "options": [
      "Risk assessment",
      "Code review",
      "Vulnerability scan",
      "Penetration test"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Penetration test is correct. A penetration test is considered an active test because you are actually interacting with the target system and trying to bypass the security controls. Incorrect answers: Vulnerability scan is incorrect. A vulnerability scan is considered a passive test because it only involves reviewing the configuration of a system to determine if there are any vulnerabilities. Risk assessment is incorrect. A risk assessment helps identify risks for each asset. Code review is incorrect. A code review involves reviewing the code of an application to look for flaws."
  },
  {
    "question": "Rebecca is the systems administrator for a small accounting firm and would like to ensure that wireless guests cannot access the company file servers. Her company has purchased a single router/switch/access point. What should she do to achieve these security goals? (Choose two.)",
    "options": [
      "Disable the file server ports.",
      "Create a VLAN for the file servers.",
      "Set the WPA2 key to a new value.",
      "Deny file server traffic on the WAN port.",
      "Configure an ACL on the router to allow access to the file server VLAN."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1,
      4
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answers: Create a VLAN for the file servers and configure an ACL on the router to allow access to the file server VLAN are correct. To control communication, Rebecca can place the servers in their own VLAN, which restricts communication by default. She can then create an ACL on the router to allow authorized systems to communicate with the file server VLAN. Incorrect answers: Deny file server traffic on the WAN port is incorrect. Disabling file server traffic on the WAN port has nothing to do with the scenario and is incorrect because Rebecca's goal is to control communication between wireless guests and company file servers (the scenario does not deal with Internet WAN traffic). Disable the file server ports is incorrect. She cannot disable the ports the file servers are connected to because that will prevent everyone from being able to communicate with them. Set the WPA2 key to a new value is incorrect. Changing the WPA2 key will not help separate wireless guest traffic from the company file servers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the practice of stealing or obtaining a user's personal or account information, typically using voice over IP (VoIP) systems?",
    "options": [
      "Whaling",
      "Vishing",
      "VoIP hijacking",
      "Phishing"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Vishing is correct. Vishing (a combination of the terms voice and phishing) refers to social engineering attacks that make use of VoIP systems to spoof phone numbers, hide caller IDs, and so forth, to obtain personal or account information from unsuspecting users. Incorrect answers: Phishing is incorrect. Phishing involves the use of e-mail targeted to users with a malicious web site link embedded in the e-mail. Whaling is incorrect. Whaling involves specifically targeting senior-level executives of an organization for social engineering attacks. VoIP hijacking is incorrect. VoIP hijacking is a nonexistent term in this context."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following formulas represents the single loss expectancy?",
    "options": [
      "SLE = value ($) × loss ($)",
      "SLE = loss ($) × EF (%)",
      "SLE = value ($) × EF (%)",
      "SLE = ALE ($) × ARO (#)"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SLE = value ($) × EF (%) is correct. The formula to compute the single loss expectancy of an asset is its value, in dollars, multiplied by the percentage of loss (exposure factor) experienced by the asset. If the value of the asset is $10,000 and the EF is 30 percent, then the SLE is $3,000. Incorrect answers: SLE = value ($) × loss ($) is incorrect. SLE is the value of the asset ($) × exposure factor (%). SLE = loss ($) × EF (%) is incorrect. SLE is the value of the asset ($) × exposure factor (%). SLE = ALE ($) × ARO (#) is incorrect. SLE is the value of the asset ($) × exposure factor (%)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements best describes an algorithm?",
    "options": [
      "A mathematical operation that is performed on the data to convert the data from plain text to cipher text (or vice versa)",
      "A mathematical function that involves comparing two bits of text to produce a bit result",
      "A value indicating the time it would take to break the encryption",
      "A variable piece of information that is used by the encryption process to perform the encryption or decryption of the data"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: A mathematical operation that is performed on the data to convert the data from plain text to cipher text (or vice versa) is correct. An algorithm is a mathematical operation that is performed on the data to convert the data from plain text to cipher text (or vice versa). Incorrect answers: A variable piece of information that is used by the encryption process to perform the encryption or decryption of the data is incorrect. A key is a variable piece of information that is used by the encryption algorithm to perform the encryption or decryption of the data. A value indicating the time it would take to break the encryption is incorrect. Work factor refers to the value indicating the time it would take to break the encryption. A mathematical function that involves comparing two bits of text to produce a bit result is incorrect. An exclusive OR (XOR) is a mathematical function that involves comparing two bits of text to produce a bit result."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of risk analysis uses ALE figures to prioritize risks?",
    "options": [
      "Subverted",
      "Quantitative",
      "Qualitative",
      "Inverted"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Quantitative is correct. Quantitative risk analysis uses dollar values (quantities) to prioritize threats. The ALE value represents a cost should the risk occur. Incorrect answers: Inverted is incorrect. Inverted analysis is an invalid term. Subverted is incorrect. Subverted risk analysis is an invalid term. Qualitative is incorrect. Qualitative risk analysis uses a relative ranking system, and not dollar values, to organize risks."
  },
  {
    "question": "What tool would you use to view the header of a file in order to verify that it is a JPG file with the starting header value of FF D8 FF E0?",
    "options": [
      "Memdump",
      "dd",
      "Netstat",
      "WinHex"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: WinHex is correct. WinHex is a hex editor that allows you to look at the raw data of a file, including the file header. Incorrect answers: dd is incorrect. dd is used to create a forensics image of a hard drive or memory. Memdump is incorrect. Memdump is used to copy the contents of memory to a file. Netstat is incorrect. Netstat is used to see a list of connections to your system."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of document identifies the uptime that should be received from a cloud service provider?",
    "options": [
      "MOU",
      "SLA",
      "NDA",
      "EOSL"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      1
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SLA is correct. The service level agreement (SLA) indicates the level of service you should expect from a provider, including uptime. Incorrect answers: MOU is incorrect. A memorandum of understanding (MOU) is a document that establishes an agreement between two parties and specifies their relationship to one another. NDA is incorrect. A nondisclosure agreement (NDA) is a document that outlines the confidentiality of the relationship between two parties and what information is considered to be confidential. EOSL is incorrect. The end of service life (EOSL) marking is typically assigned to hardware or software that is no longer supported by the vendor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of remedial security and awareness training would be most appropriate for a user who has used organizational computer assets for personal gain?",
    "options": [
      "Privacy policy training",
      "Data disposition policy training",
      "Acceptable use policy training",
      "Separation of duties policy training"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Acceptable use policy training is correct. Acceptable use policies typically cover the use of an organization's information systems for personal gain, and remediation training on this policy could be useful for a first-time or minor offender. Incorrect answers: Separation of duties policy training is incorrect. Separation of duties does not address the acceptable use of computer assets within a business. Privacy policy training is incorrect. The privacy policy does not address the acceptable use of computer assets within a business. Data disposition policy training is incorrect. Data disposition does not address the acceptable use of computer assets within a business."
  },
  {
    "question": "The chief information security officer (CISO) for your company has asked that you look into potential cloud providers that your company can subscribe to for anti-malware protection and anti-spam functionality. What type of cloud solution is this?",
    "options": [
      "SaaS",
      "PaaS",
      "IaaS",
      "XaaS"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      3
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: XaaS is correct. Anything as a Service (XaaS) is a cloud solution that involves the cloud provider offering any other services through the cloud not covered by SaaS, PaaS, or IaaS. For example, security solutions such as anti-malware, anti-spam, intrusion detection services, and penetration testing services all fall into XaaS. Incorrect answers: SaaS is incorrect. Software as a Service (SaaS) is when an application, such as Office 365 or Gmail, is provided by the cloud provider. PaaS is incorrect. Platform as a Service (PaaS) provides the computing platform for a solution, such as a development platform or database server. IaaS is incorrect. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) involves the cloud provider offering virtualization solutions to its customers."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are part of the risk management team within your company and are currently performing a risk assessment of the IT assets. You are responsible for calculating the ALE of a denial of service attack on your company web site. Which of the following formulas would you use?",
    "options": [
      "EF × ARO",
      "AV × EF",
      "SLE × ARO",
      "AV × ARO"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: SLE × ARO is correct. The annual loss expectancy (ALE) is the single loss expectancy (SLE) multiplied by the annual rate of occurrence (ARO). It should be noted that the SLE of a security event is calculated by multiplying the asset value (AV) by the exposure factor (EF). Incorrect answers: AV × EF is incorrect. ALE is not calculated by AV × EF. Instead, the SLE is calculated by this formula. EF × ARO is incorrect. EF × ARO is not the formula for calculating ALE. AV × ARO is incorrect. AV × ARO is not the formula for calculating ALE."
  },
  {
    "question": "A government official is granted an authorization level that allows her access to tax records for American citizens and other confidential data. Which term best describes this scenario?",
    "options": [
      "Confidentiality",
      "Least privilege",
      "Security clearance",
      "Authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Security clearance is correct. The official was granted a security clearance to enable her to access this confidential data. Incorrect answers: Least privilege is incorrect. Least privilege means a user has only the rights required to perform a particular duty; it is not related to authorized access. Authentication is incorrect. Authentication proves the identity of a user or computer to gain access to resources. Confidentiality is incorrect. Confidentiality refers to protecting data from being accessed by unauthorized parties; in this case, access was granted to an authorized party who had the appropriate security clearance."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves the hacker compromising a popular web site and then planting malicious code on the site so that folks who visit the site run the code and are exploited?",
    "options": [
      "SQL injection",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Watering hole",
      "Cross-site request forgery"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Watering hole is correct. A watering hole attack is when the hacker plants malicious code on a site that the intended victim will visit and run the code. Incorrect answers: Cross-site scripting is incorrect. Cross-site scripting (XSS) is when the attacker submits script code as input into a site, typically so the code is stored in the back-end database and then run by another visitor when they view the page. SQL injection is incorrect. SQL injection is when the attacker inputs database code as input into an application in order to manipulate the system or the data in the database. Cross-site request forgery is incorrect. Cross-site request forgery (CSRF) is when the attacker tricks a person into clicking a link that makes a call to another site that the user is already authenticated to. For example, the link may change the user's password on the other site."
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are considered to be effective security controls when implementing a wireless network except which one?",
    "options": [
      "WEP",
      "802.1X",
      "WPA3",
      "WPA2"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      0
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: WEP is correct. WEP is a wireless security protocol that is easily compromised through its known vulnerabilities. Incorrect answers: WPA2 is incorrect. You should use WPA2 or WPA3 encryption instead of the weaker encryption methods of WPA or WEP. 802.1X is incorrect. You can use a central authentication server with 802.1X to authenticate wireless clients that connect to the wireless network. WPA3 is incorrect. You should use WPA2 or WPA3 encryption instead of the weaker encryption methods of WPA or WEP."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes the best security practice to use when granting users elevated or administrative privileges?",
    "options": [
      "Users who require higher privileges should be placed in the Administrators group.",
      "Users who perform administrative-level tasks should be given the Domain Administrator user account name and password.",
      "Users should have a normal user account for routine tasks as well as an administrative account for tasks that require higher privileges.",
      "Administrative privileges should be granted directly to those user accounts that perform administrative-level tasks."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [
      2
    ],
    "explanation": "Correct answer: Users should have a normal user account for routine tasks as well as an administrative account for tasks that require higher privileges is correct. Users should have a normal user account for routine tasks as well as an administrative account for tasks that require higher privileges. Incorrect answers: Administrative privileges should be granted directly to those user accounts that perform administrative-level tasks is incorrect. User accounts should not be directly granted administrative privileges. Users who require higher privileges should be placed in the Administrators group is incorrect. Ordinary user-level accounts should not be placed in the Administrators group. Users who perform administrative-level tasks should be given the Domain Administrator user account name and password is incorrect. No one should be given the Domain Administrator's username and password to use on a routine basis."
  }
]